<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nyc | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/nyc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-25T11:50:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Single Founders Work Harder?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/do-single-founders-work-harder/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/do-single-founders-work-harder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was at General Assembly tonight, and like most nights I'm there, I was one of the last people there. It actually amazes me that the startup space is typically mostly cleared out by 8pm. As far as I can tell, this is true of Projective Space, New Work City, and We Work Labs as well. Weekends are equally sparse -- I basically have the run of the place on a Saturday. *</p>

<div>
<div>Do single founders work harder?</div>
<div>Do they HAVE to wok harder?</div>
</div>


<div></div>


<div>
<div>By "harder" I  mean "more hours". I am not asking, "Do single founders work better?" (I think there are a lot of reasons to suspect they don't). Maybe, as a way to compensate for the other shortcomings of being a single founder, we have to work more to have a fighting shot.</div>
</div>


<div></div>


<div>Before anyone accuses me of being self congratulatory or judgmental of teams, I'm not saying that single founders DO work harder. I'm actually asking a question to explain the phenomenon where these coworking spaces filled with teams empty out by dinner. My friend Hugo says its because New York founders are lazy, but I don't buy that.</div>


<div></div>


<div>There are certainly many penalties for being a single founder, so I wonder if they are forced to work harder/more. I'm OBSESSED with my startup, Rocket Lease. I think about rental applications incessantly. And I get to work on it whenever I want, which is more or less "when I'm awake" (I'm not suggesting this is healthy or advisable, its just what I've been doing.).</div>


<div></div>


<div>When I'm obsessed with something its really hard to keep me from doing it if I have the option. So are the startup teams  in New York not obsessed, obsessed in the privacy of their own homes, or just not putting in as many hours as single founders?</div>


<div></div>


<div>* Except for Ryan W -- that guy is a team, and he works insanely hard and good all the time. I don' understand how its possible to operate at that level, that consistently, for that long.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
