<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-19T15:29:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving to Jekyll]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/moving-to-jekyll/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T19:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/moving-to-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yep, I just did it.  I:</p>

<ul>
<li>stole the theme from Svbtle (Hey I like it, and it looks awesome -- Thanks Dustin);</li>
<li>inverted the colors (not because I like it dark, but because I want my blog to look distinctive/memorable,</li>
<li>threw my chop on there (Found a scan of it and its as good a logo as any, also memorable)</li>
<li>imported from wordpress (still links to the original images, which will almost certainly break, and I don't care)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 West Coast Road Trip: 3 weeks, 2070 miles]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been slacking from my weekly writing date with my blog because Google tells me that my site has been compromised. I keep saying I'll fix it then resume my writing, but that hasn't happened, so for now, I'm writing on a domain that has been compromised. I think that really just means I need to fix some .htaccess files, but that's a job for another day.</p>

<p>August 2012, Seattle to San Diego. 3 weeks, 2070 miles, 5 Crossfit boxes, every Whole Foods along the way.</p>

<p>The places we stopped for at least one night:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Seattle, WA</li>
    <li>Seaview, WA</li>
    <li>Portland, OR</li>
    <li>Crater Lake National Park</li>
    <li>Redding, CA</li>
    <li>San Francisco, CA</li>
    <li>Sonoma, CA</li>
    <li>Carmel/Monterey, CA</li>
    <li>Buellton, CA</li>
    <li>Los Angeles, CA</li>
    <li>San Diego, CA</li>
</ol>


<p>First decided I wanted to do this trip more than 3 years ago (probably right when A and B were getting married -- thought I might be able to hit the wedding on the way).  Well, 3 years later, thanks to M, we finally got it done.  Twas awesome.  Thought we were going to get bored and not have enough to do, but on the contrary, we ran out of things to do really fast. Didn't spend more than 2 nights anywhere and didn't get to do too much in most cities.  Lots of great scenery, good food, meeting old friends, relaxing away from real life. 'Twas awesome.</p>

<p>I've been pooh-poohing the west coast for a long time now, and now I realize my folly. West Coast &gt;&gt;&gt; NYC. hands down.</p>

<p>Highlights:</p>

<ul>
    <li>I think I love Seattle. I keep getting lucky and every time I go, its sunny and beautiful. I'm afraid if I move there it'll be dreary and foggy like everyone says it is, but I've never experienced. Seattle food was shockingly good. Salumi is overrated. Ma'ono was excellent.</li>
    <li>Steamboat Inn near Crater Lake National Park. Tiny adorable hotel on the Umpqua River where there is no cell phone reception or internet. Local Oregon wines</li>
    <li>Ashland, OR -- we passed through the Shakespeare Festival but didn't go. Cute town, would like to actually stop there next time.</li>
    <li>Very cool vintage RV rally at the Sou'wester Inn &amp; Lodge/RV park. I still want to live in an Airstream trailer. Sorry, M.</li>
    <li>Portland is adorable. I feel like I'd get bored of it quickly though. Salt and Straw is great. Would like to try more food trucks. And wtf, it IS where young people retire. All the spots we wanted to go to were packed on a Monday afternoon.</li>
    <li>TChung, great catching up.</li>
    <li>House was not as good as I remembered it from 7 years ago. Restaurants and palates change in 7 years, so I wasn't particularly surprised. Still good to find out for sure.</li>
    <li>Roli Roti is awesome. The Ferry Building is awesome. I love the abundance of Asian stuff in SF, but I don't know if I love it enough to want to live there.</li>
    <li>I was most looking forward to Monterey/Carmel to remind me of my time at music camp down there, but the fog really ruined it. How did I get the most perfect summer ever when I went before?</li>
    <li>TCho, you too. Love the bitters idea. Great to see you're rocking it, CH. Chego was great.</li>
    <li>Fuck LA traffic.</li>
    <li>I like having water in my life. Looking out over that big vast blue, whether ocean or lake, brings me inner peace.</li>
    <li>San Diego -- Also wasn't a big winner for weather, I guess we got unlucky. I don't care about zoos.  Love the idea of being able to have a house on the beach and have night time campfires. However, I didn't get the feeling that I'd love the food or people.  Angriest drivers we met on the whole road trip.</li>
</ul>


<p>2070  miles for 3 states. If we had driven 2 more hours in each direction or circled around less internally, we could have hit 3 <em>countries</em>.</p>

<p>My first real vacation in a few years, but I did still do some "work".  At some point I'd like to do a sans-computer/electronics/phone/email 4+ week vacation. One day when I've made it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Highest Highs and the Lowest Lows]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"><img title="Easy Online Rental Applications" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/rl2-300x156.png" alt="Easy Online Rental Applications" width="300" height="156" /></a>
Really high highs and really low lows... such is startup life...</p>

<p>Pretty crazy week for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a>.  I don't expect startup life to be easy, but its been a bit of a rollercoaster and I'm exhausted.</p>

<p>In the span of 48 hours, we've been evicted from our insanely gorgeous office space, had our best 2 days of business ever, gotten our credit reports (our core product) shut off by our vendor, and gotten 4 amazing interns.</p>

<h2>Highlights</h2>


<p><strong>Best office space ever:</strong> Rocket Lease has been sharing extra office space with an insanely awesome startup, KM, who has probably the most insanely gorgeous office space I've seen to date.  They gave us an unbeatable deal in the spirit of founders helping founders / startups helping startups. Unbelievable space. Just have to post some pics to brag...</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-224" title="2012-06-12 11.17.31" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57.jpg"><img title="2012-06-12 11.17.57" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-226" title="2012-06-12 11.18.26" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Amazing team and interns:</strong> We currently have 2 full timers (me + Mike) and 4 college interns (Alec, Alper, Jason, John). Mike did a phenomenal job getting really sharp, smart, entrepreneurial interns who really connect with the project, and I am/was looking forward to an awesome summer.  Anyways, team of 6. This is an important point.</p>

<p>When too much is going right, you almost have to expect something to go wrong in startup land...</p>

<p><strong>Credit report malfunction!!</strong> Due to a communication error with our credit vendor, Rocket Lease's credit reports were turned off for almost 2 days. Those 2 days happened to be the highest 2-day application submission volume we've had to date (13 applications, not a big deal in the grand scheme, but a big deal to me!).</p>

<p>When the issue was finally resolved with the credit vendor, I breathed a sigh of relief, because it was super stressful to be getting paying customers that we couldn't serve.</p>

<p><strong>Evicted!!</strong> Within an hour of the credit issue resolution, KM's landlords asked them to "remove any non-KM people from the space". Uh oh. Trouble in paradise. Now we have a team of 6 and we're evicted. Homeless team of 6 is a problem because its definitely too big for us to be using starbucks as the office now...</p>

<h2>*Sigh*</h2>


<p>So it goes. The good news is that the interns are still very upbeat and are rolling with the punches.</p>

<p>I'd still like to try to see if there's a chance we can strike a deal where the landlord will be cool with us staying, but I haven't been able to connect with them, so I'm not sure if I'm getting ignored.</p>

<p>I'm really committed to making sure the interns extract a lot of value out of this relationship, so I want to make sure we're in a stable place, but now I'm scrambling to find space.  I have a couple of leads, but I don't want to pull in favors that will end up being too costly for me in the long run, so I'm treading lightly.</p>

<p>If anyone can temporarily house 6 of us for a week or two while we try to get our feet on the ground, there will be much karma returned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcelona 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/farts/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/farts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twas fun. CM moved there, so we went for Sitges Carnivale (sort of) 2012.</p>

<p>Those guys stay up really late. Didn't realize that Barcelona identifies as independent. Reminded me that I'd like to learn Spanish. And live abroad.  That's one of my current biggest regrets.</p>

<p>The trip was really just an excuse to go drinking in Barcelona with CM, JBV, RV, HR.</p>

<p>Things that are great about Barcelona:</p>

<p>Red Solo Cup. CM getting bumped at Sitges. Dicksabers. “Hey guys, can you please make silence.” The best gin and tonics at La Royale. Montiel, best meal of 2012. Tapas 24. Pan con tomate. The realization that Gaudi was almost certainly just always on drugs. When Noelle asked me to guess what she was. Lauren from Hong Kong was awesome.</p>

<div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death of a Startup: Spaciety Post-mortem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Background</h2>


<p>For those in catchup mode, until recently I was working on a startup called Spaciety (Pronounced: SPA-siety, like combining the words SPA &amp; soCIETY. That seemed really clever until we realized nobody could figure it out.  Startup rule #1: Avoid pronunciation ambiguity).</p>


<p><span>Spaciety is dead and we killed it</span>.  AAD, JBV, and I all invested a lot of effort into Spaciety, and we ultimately folded.</p>


<p><span><strong>Spaciety is Open Table or Expedia for spas and salons. We made it easy for customers to search for and book beauty services online</strong>.</span>  I&#8217;ll save most of the sales pitch for below, but spas and salons are a $100+ billion industry that is very fragmented and poorly served by technology.  It&#8217;s a very exciting space and someone will come make a killing, but it won&#8217;t be us.</p>


<p>Startup death is part of the game, and we knew we&#8217;d have to quit if it was a dud. The hard part was killing it when we might have had something good.</p>


<h2>Why Spaciety was / is great</h2>


<p><strong>Spaciety had over 100 partner spas listing services on the website at the time we made the decision to shut it down.  Spas love the idea.</strong></p>


<p>The spa industry as a whole has a vacancy rate somewhere north of 40%.  This poses a problem for spas since their &#8220;inventory&#8221; effectively self-destructs every hour.  If you have no massage bookings today, you can&#8217;t just book twice as many massages tomorrow to cover the loss.  As a result, spas are actually quite eager to sign up with a service that helps them book off-peak hours, even at substantial discounts.</p>


<p>The real value was in providing <span><strong>variable, occupancy-based pricing</strong> model</span> that allowed spas to keep peak hours at standard rates, but progressively lower rates for off-peak hours (fancytalk for &#8220;as spa owners get more desperate&#8221;). Remember: one minute before 2pm on a Wednesday, the spa has effectively agreed to accept $0 revenue for each unbooked appointment. Spaciety sold the ability to reach an audience willing to pay more than $0 at the last minute, and that was a powerful thing.</p>


<p>This is contrary to Groupon&#8217;s or Living Social&#8217;s model where spas offer large discounts, but those coupons often go towards filling up peak hours when the spa would have been booked anyways. This hurts spa owners because they accept less revenue where they would normally make money to cover down times.  There are so many daily deal sites offering spa services that these dealhunters rarely come back and there is very little positive impact in off-peak booking rates.</p>


<p>Basically, <strong>spas wanted to use it &amp; customers were ecstatic</strong> about being able to book online.</p>


<h2>Then Spaciety said &#8220;Let there be online booking&#8221;, and there was online booking</h2>


<p>Unfortunately, I can&#8217;t claim credit for the initial build &#8212; the <strong>real stars are AAD and JBV</strong>. They were very proactive, talked to spa owners, got feedback, collaborated closely with a <a href="http://pybrew.com" target="_blank">crack team of developers</a> to build a working solution, and got the business off the ground.  They pounded pavement, called spas, <strong>flirted with spa owners</strong> (both  female and male&#8230; it was ugly&#8230;), and otherwise did whatever they had to do to sign people up.</p>


<p>I was treading water on my own startup at the time and they were minting revenue in the first week of launch. I certainly eyed their success with envy.</p>


<p>For my friends who aren&#8217;t startup people: <strong>the idea always sounds easy</strong>, but execution&#8217;s a bitch. Web startups don&#8217;t cost money to build, they cost blood, sweat, and tears. <strong>Making that first dollar is damn near impossible</strong>.  Mad props, gents.  AAD and JBV rose to the challenge and then some.  When they later invited me to officially join the team, I could not have felt more honored.</p>


<h2>Fatal flaw</h2>


<p>After the crushingly successful launch, there was an experimentation period where we tried various strategies to grow.  There&#8217;s a myth that startups follow some sort of exponential growth path (It&#8217;s just that &#8212; a myth).  The trajectory for Spaciety was more like a series of plateaus.  We took a very methodical approach to testing and measuring new strategies for growth, but we kept flatlining.  Despite this, we continued to grow both the consumer and spa sides of the business until it became clear that we would have problems scaling the business in its current form.</p>


<p>The <strong>initial plan for Spaciety was to tightly integrate with each spa&#8217;s appointment booking software</strong> and algorithmically determine optimal pricing for each appointment.  What we found was that there is no universal schedling software, or even a clear market leader.  Most booking systems don&#8217;t have easy ways to extract the data, the market is highly fragmented, there&#8217;s no dominant technology, no standard data format, adoption is highly regional, and the systems are old &#8212; &#8220;built in the early 90s&#8221; old (techsnob speak for &#8220;unusable/ancient&#8221;).</p>


<p>As an alternative, Spaciety worked with individual spas to determine what appointments were generally unbooked from week to week and listed those appointments on the site. <span><strong>Whenever an appointment was booked online, our automated system would call the spa to confirm availability</strong></span> (&#8220;If this appointment is available, press 1; if not, press 9&#8221;). The Spaciety site inventory represented a <strong>highly probable, but not guaranteed inventory</strong>, as determined based on the historical bookings of a particular spa.</p>


<p>As a result, there was<span> always some <strong>chance that a customer would book an appointment and it would be unavailable</strong></span>.  To mitigate this issue, we 1) concentrated on acquiring multiple spas in close proximity so we could direct overflow to nearby partner spas, 2) made sure spas were aware of this so they would try to be flexible squeezing in appointments for us.</p>


<p>This worked well for a while, but somewhere around 85 partner spas, AAD started spending an inordinate amount of time/effort dealing with unavailable appointments.  <strong>85 spas worth of listings, each with a small chance of being unavailable added up to a big chance of problems on any given day</strong>.  Dealing with these collisions takes more time than you&#8217;d think, and the fear that it could happen at any time worried us constantly.</p>


<p><strong>As we continued to grow, it was clear that this strategy was unsustainable.</strong></p>


<h2>Darkness</h2>


<p>It&#8217;s really frustrating to work hard, get something to start working, and only then realize that you&#8217;re tanked. </p>


<p>Imagine standing at the bottom of a deep well with fog overhead. You can&#8217;t see the top. There are 20 ladders going up, but you can&#8217;t see how high they go.  We had just climbed one of the ladders and found out that it stopped dead 30 feet up.</p>


<p>When you climb back down and look around at the other 19 ladders around you, not knowing (1) how high each will take you, or (2) <em><strong>if any of them even get to the top</strong></em>, it&#8217;s scary.  <strong>It&#8217;s demoralizing</strong>.  And we were somewhere around ladder #5 by this point.</p>


<h2>Light</h2>


<p>It was clear to us that we needed to bite the bullet and <strong>explore full integration with all the Spa Scheduling Software Systems</strong> (S4, yeah thats right, I just made up that acronym).  What we found that was that there were way <span>too many systems and almost all of them were outdated</span>.</p>


<p>We had 2 options:</p>


<ol><li><strong>Building and maintaining X packages</strong> to integrate with all the software systems</li>
<li><strong>Building our own scheduling system </strong>and defining and publishing a standard for the industry to use for appointment information (hotel industry has something similar)</li>
</ol>


<p>We quickly eliminated Option A &#8212; we didn&#8217;t want to go from &#8220;guys who are revolutionizing the spa industry&#8221; to &#8220;guys who maintain 50 different software integration modules and whose software breaks anytime an independent vendor changes their code&#8221;. And it sounded boring.</p>


<p>Option B is surprisingly compelling.  The idea was that we could <strong>leverage our existing trust with in-network spas</strong> to develop better software (we&#8217;re good at developing good software, fast) and <strong>immediately have it in a large number of spas</strong>.</p>


<p>We spoke with a lot of people about this and we settled on <span>building and <strong>distributing the software for free, then using it as a funnel for taking transaction fees</strong> on online bookings</span>.  &#8221;Owning&#8221; the centralized source of all appointment data is wildly valuable for all sorts of reasons.</p>


<p>Additionally, investors who were already interested in us really perked up because building the software and owning the data gave us<strong> defensible IP and increased barriers to entry</strong> for direct competitors.  We already understood the market, had the trust of spa owners, and know how to build next generation software.</p>


<p>We accidentally stumbled upon <strong>something investors liked more</strong>.  We flirted with funds. Contacts from our old finance careers were asking to give us money.  We literally just had to sign on the dotted line to get funding.</p>


<p>One problem: <strong>It&#8217;s a long game</strong>.  Even if we got into 100 spas today, we needed to get into 5,000 spas.  Building good software isn&#8217;t enough for that. <strong>We&#8217;d be committing to building and selling for 2 years to even find out if we had a fighting shot</strong>.</p>


<p>In the end, <span>it was another ladder into the fog</span>. We didn&#8217;t want to risk ending at the top of a really high ladder in 2 years.  If we had started this path 2 years ago, I might be writing a different story. But our lives had changed in the last 2 years (AAD, congrats on the new baby!) and the risk/reward profile of the new path no longer fit our current desires.  </p>


<p>The work would be long, the path uncertain, and the payout questionable.  Those are always true, but we were looking for something that was either more likely, less difficult, or testable on a shorter time horizon. The business profile just wasn&#8217;t right for us.</p>


<h2>Founder-startup fit</h2>


<p>Startup people spend a lot of time talking about &#8220;product-market fit&#8221;, meaning &#8220;do you have a product the market wants?&#8221; But sometimes the product-market fit is right, but the founders don&#8217;t fit the startup. When I was 23 with $475 rent, I would have run for a 2% chance at 100mm, but old man me prefers a 50% chance at 3mm. Spaciety died because the business model it forced wasn&#8217;t right for us.</p>


<p>I wonder how many startups die because of founder-startup fit. Or how many founders don&#8217;t recognize the lack of founder-startup fit and ride a trajectory to failure. The truth is, I think AAD and I were blessed with great mentors and friends; we were lucky to be able to assess the lack of fit and make the hard, but rational call to shut it down.</p>


<p>Like all stories, there&#8217;s more complexity to this one, but if you want to hear about it you&#8217;ll have to sit the 3 of us down for a drink. On you. Preferably something very expensive.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
