<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-13T11:13:46-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chicago Coffee Shops: Where I Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T07:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you're working on a startup or freelancing, you often find yourself frequenting cafes around town. If you're like me, you try to stay away from Starbucks.</p>

<p>I've compiled a list of personal favorites and recommendations from other startup friends, grouped by approximate geographic location.</p>

<p>If you're funemployed like me, have other great spots I can add to the list, or want to join the Chicago Daytime Coffeeshop Circuit, or "CDCC" as I like to call it (yep, I just made that up), drop a line: <a href="mailto:ezl@rocketlease.com">ipoopdaily@rocketlease.com</a></p>

<p>My personal favorites from below: Sip, Little Branch, Next Door Cafe, Wormhole, Floriole</p>

<h2>Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.pumproom.com/">Public Hotel</a> - Hotel lobby has a cafe in it with a huge work table. Work in luxurious surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://lmrestaurant.com/home.html">LM Bistro -- Hotel Felix bar</a> - I generally come here in the afternoons if I want to booze while I work. Great bourbon selection. Wifi: Free but spotty.</li>
<li><a href="http://wholefoodsmarket.com/stores/lincolnpark">Whole Foods North Ave</a> - Awesome. Huge work area on the second floor. Great food downstairs and a coffee bar. Also 6.00 bourbon pours and lots of great beer. Wifi: 2 hour limit, then just refresh your browser cookies; Huge plus == free parking.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/panera-bread-chicago-14">Panera @ Division/Sedgewick</a> - Eh, it's Panera. But you can park, so I come occasionally.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/starbucks-chicago-114">Starbucks Pipers Alley</a> - Eh, its starbucks, but its big so its easy to work with others here. Wifi its often brutal.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/ing-direct-cafe-chicago">ING Direct Cafe</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafedesarchitectes.com/">Cafe Des Architects</a> - Sofitel hotel restaurant - dead on weekdays and they're happy to have you just sit in. Gorgeous sunlit room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.delightfulpastries.com/">Delightful Pastries</a> - Lincoln park bakery, also dead on weekdays with nice staff. Tea isn't cheap: $4.38. Pastries are cloyingly sweet. But 4.38 to rent an office for the afternoon works for me.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/elaines-coffee-call-chicago">Elaines Coffee Call</a> - Very cute spot in the Lincoln Hotel. Great almond milk latte.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/evas-cafe-chicago-2">Evas</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Near But Not As Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.uncommonground.com/">Uncommon Ground</a> - Only been to the Wrigleyville one. Nice big windows to let in the sun.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nextdoorchi.com/">Next Door Cafe</a> - Lets you book conference rooms for free, great restaurants nearby, and if you're feeling adventurous, you can park at Trader Joe's next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.floriole.com/">Floriole</a> - Best pastries in the city. Wifi is usually good. Staff is generally nice, but J can get a little snarky if he thinks you're sitting there too long.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thebourgeoispigcafe.com/">The Bourgeois Pig</a> - Classic spot, old two story house. Can get crowded.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.citygroundschicago.com/">Citygrounds</a> - Typically a good hideaway that stays pretty quiet, even on weekends.</li>
<li><a href="http://bowtruss.com/">Bow Truss</a> - Terrible spot to work, they're really a roaster. No idea why I'm leaving this on the list. Very sexy website though.</li>
<li><a href="http://kickstandcoffee.com/">Kickstand</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.coffeeandtea.com/">Coffee and Tea</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Even More North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/kopi-travelers-cafe-chicago">Kopi Travelers</a> - No Wifi, but i REALLY dig the atmosphere here. Get one of the spots by the window entrance its like a hippie Japanese tatami room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thecoffeestudio.com/">Coffee Studio</a> - Modern minimalist coffee shop with great espresso. Unforunately it often packs out.</li>
<li><a href="http://chavacafe.com/">Chava</a> - I think this place was supposed to be a Starbucks, but then corporate backed out. Chava got a great, built out spot.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bookcellarinc.com/cafe">Book Cellar</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.asadocoffee.com/">Asado</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dollopcoffee.com/">Dollop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/julius-meinl-chicago-2">Julius Meinl</a> - Packs out. Nice pastries</li>
</ul>


<h2>So Far North It Might As Well Be Wisconsin</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.metropoliscoffee.com/">Metropolis</a> - Too far away, but if you're in this hood, a good work spot.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Near West</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/sip-coffee-house-and-garden-chicago">Sip</a> - Personal favorite. This is in my top 3. Cheap tea, cool staff, awesome vibe. Park on Hubbard.</li>
<li><a href="http://swimcafe.com/">Swim Cafe</a> - Big open room can get cold and loud. Good food though. Can typically find parking in front of the school next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://bigshoulderscoffee.com/">Big Shoulders Coffee</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.lovelybakeshop.com/home.php">Lovely</a> - Kind of a weird spot, its typically second place if swim is full.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/letizias-natural-bakery-chicago">Letizia's Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jupiteroutpost.com/">Jupiter Outpost</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Old HipsterVille South (Wicker/Ukranian Village-ish)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Atomix-Coffee-Shop/83455341497">Atomix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafeballouchicago.com/">Cafe Ballou</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.knockboxcafe.com/">Knockbox</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.alliance-bakery.com/">Alliance Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.prasino.com/locations_chicago.html">Prasino</a> - Don't go on weekends, you'll be stepping on their lunch service, but during the week its wide open.  A little smug, but I love the big windows.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffestreets.com/">Caffe Streets</a> - I think this place gets too loud, but my friends dig it.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Old Hipsterville North (Bucktown)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://thewormhole.us/">Wormhole</a> - They have an old school Nintendo. That is all that matters.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/filter-chicago">Filter</a> - Spotty. Go to Wormhole.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffedeluca.com/">Caffe Deluca</a> - Not really the best work spot, but you can camp out for 2 hours or so and get great food.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.redjunecafe.com/">Red June</a> - Great all day work spot, but not the "warmest" surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://bonbonsandwiches.com/">Bon Bon</a> - Eclectic decor, free wifi, great Vietnamese sandwiches. Proprieter, Tim, is a nice dude.</li>
</ul>


<h2>South</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.artists-cafe.com/">Artists Cafe</a> -- Conveniently near MT's house or I wouldn't ever go.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.littlebranchcafe.com/">Little Branch</a> -- Even more convenient so this is pretty much the only South Loop spot I hit.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.overflowcoffeebar.org/">Overflow</a> -- Weirdly barren.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.efebinascafe.com/">Efebina's</a> -- Decent spot if you're close to Chinatown</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/cafe-jumping-bean-chicago">Jumping Bean</a> -- Not that great, but the only thing I know of near Honky Tonk BBQ.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bridgeportcoffeecompany.com/">Bridgeport Coffee Company</a> -- Good spot, street parking, but not worth the trek for me.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving to Jekyll]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/moving-to-jekyll/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T19:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/moving-to-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yep, I just did it.  I:</p>

<ul>
<li>stole the theme from Svbtle (Hey I like it, and it looks awesome -- Thanks Dustin);</li>
<li>inverted the colors (not because I like it dark, but because I want my blog to look distinctive/memorable,</li>
<li>threw my chop on there (Found a scan of it and its as good a logo as any, also memorable)</li>
<li>imported from wordpress (still links to the original images, which will almost certainly break, and I don't care)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 West Coast Road Trip: 3 weeks, 2070 miles]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been slacking from my weekly writing date with my blog because Google tells me that my site has been compromised. I keep saying I'll fix it then resume my writing, but that hasn't happened, so for now, I'm writing on a domain that has been compromised. I think that really just means I need to fix some .htaccess files, but that's a job for another day.</p>

<p>August 2012, Seattle to San Diego. 3 weeks, 2070 miles, 5 Crossfit boxes, every Whole Foods along the way.</p>

<p>The places we stopped for at least one night:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Seattle, WA</li>
    <li>Seaview, WA</li>
    <li>Portland, OR</li>
    <li>Crater Lake National Park</li>
    <li>Redding, CA</li>
    <li>San Francisco, CA</li>
    <li>Sonoma, CA</li>
    <li>Carmel/Monterey, CA</li>
    <li>Buellton, CA</li>
    <li>Los Angeles, CA</li>
    <li>San Diego, CA</li>
</ol>


<p>First decided I wanted to do this trip more than 3 years ago (probably right when A and B were getting married -- thought I might be able to hit the wedding on the way).  Well, 3 years later, thanks to M, we finally got it done.  Twas awesome.  Thought we were going to get bored and not have enough to do, but on the contrary, we ran out of things to do really fast. Didn't spend more than 2 nights anywhere and didn't get to do too much in most cities.  Lots of great scenery, good food, meeting old friends, relaxing away from real life. 'Twas awesome.</p>

<p>I've been pooh-poohing the west coast for a long time now, and now I realize my folly. West Coast &gt;&gt;&gt; NYC. hands down.</p>

<p>Highlights:</p>

<ul>
    <li>I think I love Seattle. I keep getting lucky and every time I go, its sunny and beautiful. I'm afraid if I move there it'll be dreary and foggy like everyone says it is, but I've never experienced. Seattle food was shockingly good. Salumi is overrated. Ma'ono was excellent.</li>
    <li>Steamboat Inn near Crater Lake National Park. Tiny adorable hotel on the Umpqua River where there is no cell phone reception or internet. Local Oregon wines</li>
    <li>Ashland, OR -- we passed through the Shakespeare Festival but didn't go. Cute town, would like to actually stop there next time.</li>
    <li>Very cool vintage RV rally at the Sou'wester Inn &amp; Lodge/RV park. I still want to live in an Airstream trailer. Sorry, M.</li>
    <li>Portland is adorable. I feel like I'd get bored of it quickly though. Salt and Straw is great. Would like to try more food trucks. And wtf, it IS where young people retire. All the spots we wanted to go to were packed on a Monday afternoon.</li>
    <li>TChung, great catching up.</li>
    <li>House was not as good as I remembered it from 7 years ago. Restaurants and palates change in 7 years, so I wasn't particularly surprised. Still good to find out for sure.</li>
    <li>Roli Roti is awesome. The Ferry Building is awesome. I love the abundance of Asian stuff in SF, but I don't know if I love it enough to want to live there.</li>
    <li>I was most looking forward to Monterey/Carmel to remind me of my time at music camp down there, but the fog really ruined it. How did I get the most perfect summer ever when I went before?</li>
    <li>TCho, you too. Love the bitters idea. Great to see you're rocking it, CH. Chego was great.</li>
    <li>Fuck LA traffic.</li>
    <li>I like having water in my life. Looking out over that big vast blue, whether ocean or lake, brings me inner peace.</li>
    <li>San Diego -- Also wasn't a big winner for weather, I guess we got unlucky. I don't care about zoos.  Love the idea of being able to have a house on the beach and have night time campfires. However, I didn't get the feeling that I'd love the food or people.  Angriest drivers we met on the whole road trip.</li>
</ul>


<p>2070  miles for 3 states. If we had driven 2 more hours in each direction or circled around less internally, we could have hit 3 <em>countries</em>.</p>

<p>My first real vacation in a few years, but I did still do some "work".  At some point I'd like to do a sans-computer/electronics/phone/email 4+ week vacation. One day when I've made it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Highest Highs and the Lowest Lows]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"><img title="Easy Online Rental Applications" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/rl2-300x156.png" alt="Easy Online Rental Applications" width="300" height="156" /></a>
Really high highs and really low lows... such is startup life...</p>

<p>Pretty crazy week for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a>.  I don't expect startup life to be easy, but its been a bit of a rollercoaster and I'm exhausted.</p>

<p>In the span of 48 hours, we've been evicted from our insanely gorgeous office space, had our best 2 days of business ever, gotten our credit reports (our core product) shut off by our vendor, and gotten 4 amazing interns.</p>

<h2>Highlights</h2>


<p><strong>Best office space ever:</strong> Rocket Lease has been sharing extra office space with an insanely awesome startup, KM, who has probably the most insanely gorgeous office space I've seen to date.  They gave us an unbeatable deal in the spirit of founders helping founders / startups helping startups. Unbelievable space. Just have to post some pics to brag...</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-224" title="2012-06-12 11.17.31" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57.jpg"><img title="2012-06-12 11.17.57" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-226" title="2012-06-12 11.18.26" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Amazing team and interns:</strong> We currently have 2 full timers (me + Mike) and 4 college interns (Alec, Alper, Jason, John). Mike did a phenomenal job getting really sharp, smart, entrepreneurial interns who really connect with the project, and I am/was looking forward to an awesome summer.  Anyways, team of 6. This is an important point.</p>

<p>When too much is going right, you almost have to expect something to go wrong in startup land...</p>

<p><strong>Credit report malfunction!!</strong> Due to a communication error with our credit vendor, Rocket Lease's credit reports were turned off for almost 2 days. Those 2 days happened to be the highest 2-day application submission volume we've had to date (13 applications, not a big deal in the grand scheme, but a big deal to me!).</p>

<p>When the issue was finally resolved with the credit vendor, I breathed a sigh of relief, because it was super stressful to be getting paying customers that we couldn't serve.</p>

<p><strong>Evicted!!</strong> Within an hour of the credit issue resolution, KM's landlords asked them to "remove any non-KM people from the space". Uh oh. Trouble in paradise. Now we have a team of 6 and we're evicted. Homeless team of 6 is a problem because its definitely too big for us to be using starbucks as the office now...</p>

<h2>*Sigh*</h2>


<p>So it goes. The good news is that the interns are still very upbeat and are rolling with the punches.</p>

<p>I'd still like to try to see if there's a chance we can strike a deal where the landlord will be cool with us staying, but I haven't been able to connect with them, so I'm not sure if I'm getting ignored.</p>

<p>I'm really committed to making sure the interns extract a lot of value out of this relationship, so I want to make sure we're in a stable place, but now I'm scrambling to find space.  I have a couple of leads, but I don't want to pull in favors that will end up being too costly for me in the long run, so I'm treading lightly.</p>

<p>If anyone can temporarily house 6 of us for a week or two while we try to get our feet on the ground, there will be much karma returned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
