<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-30T16:34:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 West Coast Road Trip: 3 weeks, 2070 miles]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/2012-west-coast-road-trip-3-weeks-2070-miles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been slacking from my weekly writing date with my blog because Google tells me that my site has been compromised. I keep saying I'll fix it then resume my writing, but that hasn't happened, so for now, I'm writing on a domain that has been compromised. I think that really just means I need to fix some .htaccess files, but that's a job for another day.</p>

<p>August 2012, Seattle to San Diego. 3 weeks, 2070 miles, 5 Crossfit boxes, every Whole Foods along the way.</p>

<p>The places we stopped for at least one night:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Seattle, WA</li>
    <li>Seaview, WA</li>
    <li>Portland, OR</li>
    <li>Crater Lake National Park</li>
    <li>Redding, CA</li>
    <li>San Francisco, CA</li>
    <li>Sonoma, CA</li>
    <li>Carmel/Monterey, CA</li>
    <li>Buellton, CA</li>
    <li>Los Angeles, CA</li>
    <li>San Diego, CA</li>
</ol>


<p>First decided I wanted to do this trip more than 3 years ago (probably right when A and B were getting married -- thought I might be able to hit the wedding on the way).  Well, 3 years later, thanks to M, we finally got it done.  Twas awesome.  Thought we were going to get bored and not have enough to do, but on the contrary, we ran out of things to do really fast. Didn't spend more than 2 nights anywhere and didn't get to do too much in most cities.  Lots of great scenery, good food, meeting old friends, relaxing away from real life. 'Twas awesome.</p>

<p>I've been pooh-poohing the west coast for a long time now, and now I realize my folly. West Coast &gt;&gt;&gt; NYC. hands down.</p>

<p>Highlights:</p>

<ul>
    <li>I think I love Seattle. I keep getting lucky and every time I go, its sunny and beautiful. I'm afraid if I move there it'll be dreary and foggy like everyone says it is, but I've never experienced. Seattle food was shockingly good. Salumi is overrated. Ma'ono was excellent.</li>
    <li>Steamboat Inn near Crater Lake National Park. Tiny adorable hotel on the Umpqua River where there is no cell phone reception or internet. Local Oregon wines</li>
    <li>Ashland, OR -- we passed through the Shakespeare Festival but didn't go. Cute town, would like to actually stop there next time.</li>
    <li>Very cool vintage RV rally at the Sou'wester Inn &amp; Lodge/RV park. I still want to live in an Airstream trailer. Sorry, M.</li>
    <li>Portland is adorable. I feel like I'd get bored of it quickly though. Salt and Straw is great. Would like to try more food trucks. And wtf, it IS where young people retire. All the spots we wanted to go to were packed on a Monday afternoon.</li>
    <li>TChung, great catching up.</li>
    <li>House was not as good as I remembered it from 7 years ago. Restaurants and palates change in 7 years, so I wasn't particularly surprised. Still good to find out for sure.</li>
    <li>Roli Roti is awesome. The Ferry Building is awesome. I love the abundance of Asian stuff in SF, but I don't know if I love it enough to want to live there.</li>
    <li>I was most looking forward to Monterey/Carmel to remind me of my time at music camp down there, but the fog really ruined it. How did I get the most perfect summer ever when I went before?</li>
    <li>TCho, you too. Love the bitters idea. Great to see you're rocking it, CH. Chego was great.</li>
    <li>Fuck LA traffic.</li>
    <li>I like having water in my life. Looking out over that big vast blue, whether ocean or lake, brings me inner peace.</li>
    <li>San Diego -- Also wasn't a big winner for weather, I guess we got unlucky. I don't care about zoos.  Love the idea of being able to have a house on the beach and have night time campfires. However, I didn't get the feeling that I'd love the food or people.  Angriest drivers we met on the whole road trip.</li>
</ul>


<p>2070  miles for 3 states. If we had driven 2 more hours in each direction or circled around less internally, we could have hit 3 <em>countries</em>.</p>

<p>My first real vacation in a few years, but I did still do some "work".  At some point I'd like to do a sans-computer/electronics/phone/email 4+ week vacation. One day when I've made it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
