<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-25T11:52:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chicago Coffee Shops: Where I Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T07:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you're working on a startup or freelancing, you often find yourself frequenting cafes around town. If you're like me, you try to stay away from Starbucks.</p>

<p>I've compiled a list of personal favorites and recommendations from other startup friends, grouped by approximate geographic location.</p>

<p>If you're funemployed like me, have other great spots I can add to the list, or want to join the Chicago Daytime Coffeeshop Circuit, or "CDCC" as I like to call it (yep, I just made that up), drop a line: ipoopdaily@rocketlease.com</p>

<h2>Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.pumproom.com/">Public Hotel</a> - Hotel lobby has a cafe in it with a huge work table. Work in luxurious surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://lmrestaurant.com/home.html">LM Bistro -- Hotel Felix bar</a> - I generally come here in the afternoons if I want to booze while I work. Great bourbon selection. Wifi: Free but spotty.</li>
<li><a href="http://wholefoodsmarket.com/stores/lincolnpark">Whole Foods North Ave</a> - Awesome. Huge work area on the second floor. Great food downstairs and a coffee bar. Also 6.00 bourbon pours and lots of great beer. Wifi: 2 hour limit, then just refresh your browser cookies; Huge plus == free parking.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/panera-bread-chicago-14">Panera @ Division/Sedgewick</a> - Eh, it's Panera. But you can park, so I come occasionally.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/starbucks-chicago-114">Starbucks Pipers Alley</a> - Eh, its starbucks, but its big so its easy to work with others here. Wifi its often brutal.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/ing-direct-cafe-chicago">ING Direct Cafe</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafedesarchitectes.com/">Cafe Des Architects</a> - Sofitel hotel restaurant - dead on weekdays and they're happy to have you just sit in. Gorgeous sunlit room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.delightfulpastries.com/">Delightful Pastries</a> - Lincoln park bakery, also dead on weekdays with nice staff. Tea isn't cheap: $4.38. Pastries are cloyingly sweet. But 4.38 to rent an office for the afternoon works for me.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/elaines-coffee-call-chicago">Elaines Coffee Call</a> - Very cute spot in the Lincoln Hotel. Great almond milk latte.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/evas-cafe-chicago-2">Evas</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Near But Not As Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.uncommonground.com/">Uncommon Ground</a> - Only been to the Wrigleyville one. Nice big windows to let in the sun.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nextdoorchi.com/">Next Door Cafe</a> - Lets you book conference rooms for free, great restaurants nearby, and if you're feeling adventurous, you can park at Trader Joe's next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.floriole.com/">Floriole</a> - Best pastries in the city. Wifi is usually good. Staff is generally nice, but J can get a little snarky if he thinks you're sitting there too long.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thebourgeoispigcafe.com/">The Bourgeois Pig</a> - Classic spot, old two story house. Can get crowded.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.citygroundschicago.com/">Citygrounds</a> - Typically a good hideaway that stays pretty quiet, even on weekends.</li>
<li><a href="http://bowtruss.com/">Bow Truss</a> - Terrible spot to work, they're really a roaster. No idea why I'm leaving this on the list. Very sexy website though.</li>
<li><a href="http://kickstandcoffee.com/">Kickstand</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.coffeeandtea.com/">Coffee and Tea</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Even More North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/kopi-travelers-cafe-chicago">Kopi Travelers</a> - No Wifi, but i REALLY dig the atmosphere here. Get one of the spots by the window entrance its like a hippie Japanese tatami room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thecoffeestudio.com/">Coffee Studio</a> - Modern minimalist coffee shop with great espresso. Unforunately it often packs out.</li>
<li><a href="http://chavacafe.com/">Chava</a> - I think this place was supposed to be a Starbucks, but then corporate backed out. Chava got a great, built out spot.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bookcellarinc.com/cafe">Book Cellar</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.asadocoffee.com/">Asado</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dollopcoffee.com/">Dollop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/julius-meinl-chicago-2">Julius Meinl</a> - Packs out. Nice pastries</li>
</ul>


<h2>So Far North It Might As Well Be Wisconsin</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.metropoliscoffee.com/">Metropolis</a> - Too far away, but if you're in this hood, a good work spot.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Near West</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/sip-coffee-house-and-garden-chicago">Sip</a> - Personal favorite. This is in my top 3. Cheap tea, cool staff, awesome vibe. Park on Hubbard.</li>
<li><a href="http://swimcafe.com/">Swim Cafe</a> - Big open room can get cold and loud. Good food though. Can typically find parking in front of the school next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://bigshoulderscoffee.com/">Big Shoulders Coffee</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.lovelybakeshop.com/home.php">Lovely</a> - Kind of a weird spot, its typically second place if swim is full.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/letizias-natural-bakery-chicago">Letizia's Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jupiteroutpost.com/">Jupiter Outpost</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Old HipsterVille South (Wicker/Ukranian Village-ish)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Atomix-Coffee-Shop/83455341497">Atomix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafeballouchicago.com/">Cafe Ballou</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.knockboxcafe.com/">Knockbox</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.alliance-bakery.com/">Alliance Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.prasino.com/locations_chicago.html">Prasino</a> - Don't go on weekends, you'll be stepping on their lunch service, but during the week its wide open.  A little smug, but I love the big windows.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffestreets.com/">Caffe Streets</a> - I think this place gets too loud, but my friends dig it.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Old Hipsterville North (Bucktown)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://thewormhole.us/">Wormhole</a> - They have an old school Nintendo. That is all that matters.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/filter-chicago">Filter</a> - Spotty. Go to Wormhole.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffedeluca.com/">Caffe Deluca</a> - Not really the best work spot, but you can camp out for 2 hours or so and get great food.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.redjunecafe.com/">Red June</a> - Great all day work spot, but not the "warmest" surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://bonbonsandwiches.com/">Bon Bon</a> - Eclectic decor, free wifi, great Vietnamese sandwiches. Proprieter, Tim, is a nice dude.</li>
</ul>


<h2>South</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.artists-cafe.com/">Artists Cafe</a> -- Conveniently near MT's house or I wouldn't ever go.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.littlebranchcafe.com/">Little Branch</a> -- Even more convenient so this is pretty much the only South Loop spot I hit.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.overflowcoffeebar.org/">Overflow</a> -- Weirdly barren.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.efebinascafe.com/">Efebina's</a> -- Decent spot if you're close to Chinatown</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/cafe-jumping-bean-chicago">Jumping Bean</a> -- Not that great, but the only thing I know of near Honky Tonk BBQ.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bridgeportcoffeecompany.com/">Bridgeport Coffee Company</a> -- Good spot, street parking, but not worth the trek for me.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Equity Pool / Founder Failure Insurance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T10:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My startup is unlikely to succeed. Your startup is unlikely to succeed.</p>

<p>Does anyone want to throw a couple points of equity into a pool to hedge their bets? I like to think of this as "founder failure insurance".</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: I have no idea what the legal ramifications of this are, and the details are definitely tricky.  Critics will almost certainly say "this is impossible legally" and/or "this would never work in practice".</p>

<p>I know that <em>I</em> personally, for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> would be interested in hedging my success in a portfolio with other founders.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>I don't know how it works. I know that a naive flavor of this, in its simplest form, looks something like:</p>

<div class="note">
<p>10 founders get together, donate 3% of their respective companies to a pool in return for 10% of the returns of the portfolio.</p>

<p>Then maybe something like 7 founders fail, 1 breaks even, 1 gets acquired, and 1 makes a real run for the big bucks.  The ones that failed end up making a little back since they're part of the pool. The big winner gives up a little of the company returns, but hopefully he's not a greedy bastard and he is still happy that he paid a little insurance in case he was one of the failures.</p>
</div>


<p>Ideally if your startup succeeds, you get disproportionately large returns and you're so rich anyway you don't remember what piddling amounts like 3% of your company were.</p>

<h2>Gotchas</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Voting</strong> -- As a group, you'd want to invest in only good bets (insurance companies don't like insuring risky people either).  However, great founders and great ideas fail too, sometimes for reasons outside their control. The group probably can't just let companies in willy nilly, because bad founders would be incentivized to join the pool, contribute equity that becomes ultimately worthless, and reap the rewards of others. Some quorum would probably have to vote in new members.</li>
<li><strong>Failure</strong> -- what happens with failures? The entire point of the pool is to make something even when you fail.</li>
<li><strong>Dilution</strong> -- I imagine that founders probably just give x% of the equity when joining the fund and it just gets diluted out with future investment and such.  Can't do anything special here because we don't want the pool to penalize the companies chances of success (investors who don't like ugly cap tables or weird preferred shares)</li>
<li><strong>Variable Contribution/Buy-In</strong> -- maybe some founders only want to give up 1% and another founder wants to donate 10%. Should unequal contributions be allowed? Or just tell everybody they're in for 3% in return for an equal share of the resulting portfolio? If variable contributions are allowed, the pool quorum has to determine what amount of the prospective portfolio company they want in return</li>
<li><strong>Buying Out / Quitting</strong> -- Buying out your poriton of the pool? Is this legit? The pool doesn't want the next Heroku's founders to buy out their shares right before they know they're going to get bought.  At the same time, we don't want high performing companies to get penalized with the addition of a lot of garbage companies.</li>
<li><strong>Management Fee</strong> -- Legal isn't cheap. Give an attorney 30 basis points to keep him happy? And does the fund need a manager? Obviously as a participant, I want it to be as cheap as possible for myself, but I'd also love to not be the one in charge of managing this.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Why I want to do this</h2>

<p>I think this would be a fun idea, but I don't know if its feasible or what the details would have to look like. If you are a critic, please tell me why it sucks (and preferably, how it can be workable). If you are interested, please tell me so we can start scheming. <a href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Email me.</a></p>

<p>One cool thing about this is that it also gives participants a pool of other (hopefully high quality) founders that they are personally invested in seeing succeed. Participants might also see interesting dealflow from other early stage startups.</p>

<p>There doesn't have to be just one of these.  Any group of founder friends who is interested in equity swapping can do so, with their own private agreements.</p>

<p>This is the result of a conversation a few nights ago at 25 degrees with CG and CQ. I had previously also spoken with JF at the Brandery about this.  All have expressed some interest in exploring this, so might already have a few people in on this.</p>

<p><a style="color:#D20606; font-size:1.5em; text-decoration:underline;" href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Join in on the fun</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YourSiteCouldLookLike.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old gym has a website that renders terribly on mobile, yet everybody at the gym goes to it every day to see the workout (that may sound weird, just trust me that it's a typical crossfit gym thing).</p>

<p>Everybody goes to the site every day to see ONE thing: the workout of the day.  Then you get there and have to pinch and zoom to read it.</p>

<p>I want a mobile version. So I threw together my own stylesheet for it. It'd be great if I could show my friends.</p>

<h2><strong>Somebody Please Build This</strong></h2>


<p><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com</strong></p>

<p>"Your Site Could Look Like" is a website. Sort of like <strong>bitly, but it doesn't just redirect, it loads the target page AND adds additional stylesheet rules</strong> to it. Basically, it lets you apply any css to any website and show it off to your friends (or the customer who you are trying to woo).</p>

<h2><strong>How it works</strong></h2>


<p>On the main page there are 2 input fields and a submit button.</p>

<blockquote>
<div>1) Target Site URL:</div>
<div>2) CSS file location:</div>
<div>3) [Submit button]</div>
</blockquote>


<p>User puts in a website and an alt stylesheet for it. On clicking submit, they get back a unique url:</p>

<blockquote>
<div><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com/xT6j2</strong></div></blockquote>


<p>Set up an nginx/apache reverse proxy. Whenever someone accesses that URL, the service curls the target site (1), inserts the contents of the CSS file immediately before the closing html tag (2), then serves the page to the customer.</p>

<p>If you want to be fancy, you can count page views, do analytics on the ip addresses that access it, etc. You can also let people insert their own js file. Will someone build this please?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Highest Highs and the Lowest Lows]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/the-highest-highs-and-the-lowest-lows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"><img title="Easy Online Rental Applications" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/rl2-300x156.png" alt="Easy Online Rental Applications" width="300" height="156" /></a>
Really high highs and really low lows... such is startup life...</p>

<p>Pretty crazy week for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a>.  I don't expect startup life to be easy, but its been a bit of a rollercoaster and I'm exhausted.</p>

<p>In the span of 48 hours, we've been evicted from our insanely gorgeous office space, had our best 2 days of business ever, gotten our credit reports (our core product) shut off by our vendor, and gotten 4 amazing interns.</p>

<h2>Highlights</h2>


<p><strong>Best office space ever:</strong> Rocket Lease has been sharing extra office space with an insanely awesome startup, KM, who has probably the most insanely gorgeous office space I've seen to date.  They gave us an unbeatable deal in the spirit of founders helping founders / startups helping startups. Unbelievable space. Just have to post some pics to brag...</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-224" title="2012-06-12 11.17.31" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.31-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57.jpg"><img title="2012-06-12 11.17.57" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.17.57-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-226" title="2012-06-12 11.18.26" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/2012-06-12-11.18.26-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Amazing team and interns:</strong> We currently have 2 full timers (me + Mike) and 4 college interns (Alec, Alper, Jason, John). Mike did a phenomenal job getting really sharp, smart, entrepreneurial interns who really connect with the project, and I am/was looking forward to an awesome summer.  Anyways, team of 6. This is an important point.</p>

<p>When too much is going right, you almost have to expect something to go wrong in startup land...</p>

<p><strong>Credit report malfunction!!</strong> Due to a communication error with our credit vendor, Rocket Lease's credit reports were turned off for almost 2 days. Those 2 days happened to be the highest 2-day application submission volume we've had to date (13 applications, not a big deal in the grand scheme, but a big deal to me!).</p>

<p>When the issue was finally resolved with the credit vendor, I breathed a sigh of relief, because it was super stressful to be getting paying customers that we couldn't serve.</p>

<p><strong>Evicted!!</strong> Within an hour of the credit issue resolution, KM's landlords asked them to "remove any non-KM people from the space". Uh oh. Trouble in paradise. Now we have a team of 6 and we're evicted. Homeless team of 6 is a problem because its definitely too big for us to be using starbucks as the office now...</p>

<h2>*Sigh*</h2>


<p>So it goes. The good news is that the interns are still very upbeat and are rolling with the punches.</p>

<p>I'd still like to try to see if there's a chance we can strike a deal where the landlord will be cool with us staying, but I haven't been able to connect with them, so I'm not sure if I'm getting ignored.</p>

<p>I'm really committed to making sure the interns extract a lot of value out of this relationship, so I want to make sure we're in a stable place, but now I'm scrambling to find space.  I have a couple of leads, but I don't want to pull in favors that will end up being too costly for me in the long run, so I'm treading lightly.</p>

<p>If anyone can temporarily house 6 of us for a week or two while we try to get our feet on the ground, there will be much karma returned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popular Craigslist Spam Tactics for Profit (and for Evil)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/craigslist/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/craigslist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've always enjoyed <a href="http://davegooden.com/2011/05/how-airbnb-became-a-billion-dollar-company/">Dave Gooden's fantastic writeup</a> about how AirBnB benefitted from email marketing tactics on Craigslist and wondered how prevalent the use of such tactics was. (It'd also be interesting to know if that happens a lot <em>more</em> after his blog post was published)</p>

<p>Mike L and I were chatting about it and I decided to chronicle a few craigslist scam/spam/marketing techniques we've seen (with <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/">links to the actual email threads in each section</a>)</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-205" title="kimmie" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/kimmie.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="320" /></p>

<h2><strong>"Unthreatening Potential Female Roommate Just Wants Confirmation That You Can Pay Bills"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Please Run A Credit Check"
<strong>Actual Example:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental1.html">credit</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Free Credit Report.com</p>

<p>Mike was looking for a new apartment and responded to an ad in the roommates section. A cute girl responded.</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Female responder, girls get better response rates, especially cute ones.</li>
    <li>Wants to make sure you're not a scammer</li>
    <li>Well written email, very conversational, disarming.</li>
    <li>This email is too well crafted, it is unlikely to have been sent through a text spinner -- which means that its probably more targeted, and the risk of being sent to spam folders is much higher.</li>
    <li>Really LONG email. Seriously, whoever did this should rethink it, because nobody reads emails that long. Or is it part of the play? It clearly COULDN'T be a spam message!</li>
    <li>Girl is believably cute, not devastatingly hot.</li>
    <li>Eating ice cream in the picture. Come on, how non-threatening is that?</li>
    <li>Asks you to send her credit check info, but as a helpful citizen tells you to make sure to withold your SSN. Again, she's not a scammer! Conveniently recommends FreeCreditReport.com</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Their action:</strong> There are two common plays here.</p>

<ul>
    <li>post ads on craigslist seeking roommates. Whenever someone responds, send them this email encouraging them to try out freecreditreport.com</li>
    <li>Respond to ads where people are seeking roomates. If they respond back, game on.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Benefit of this:</strong> HUGE reduction of total email send volume, everyone who responds to you is already qualifying themselves as an interested candidate and giving you a real email address.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/banana.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-78" title="banana" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/banana-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>

<h2><strong>"Helpful Internet Citizen Trying To Help You Avoid Contractor Woes"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>Note:</strong> This spam was found to be a third party abusing an affiliate program. The actual company reached out and informed me that they don't condone that behavior and have banned the affiliate marketer. Their logo above was replaced by a photo of a banana. Why? Because I happened to have one in my Wordpress Media Library.</p>

<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Let Me Recommend A Site I've Used Successfully"
<strong>Actual Example:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/odesk.html">contractor site</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> An contracting site</p>

<p>I was looking for someone to reskin a wordpress blog for me. A very helpful girl named Ava who recently had a bad craigslist experience wanted to let me know that a specific contracting site gave her better results.</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Short and sweet</li>
    <li>Also from a girl</li>
    <li>Voice a common concern, just trying to save you the trouble she went through.</li>
    <li>Smoking gun: the link doesn't go to the site itself. it goes to a click tracking site. Regular humans don't do that.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Their action:</strong> scrape craigslist computer gigs section, respond to everyone and recommend a specific site as a superior alternative.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/scam2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-209" title="scam" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/scam2.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="190" /></a></p>




<h2></h2>


<h2><strong>"Christian In West Africa Wants To Rent Lovely Home To You"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Give Me All Your Info"
<strong>Actual Examples:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2a.html">[a]</a> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2b.html">[b]</a> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2c.html">[c]</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Some scammer/identity thief (This is the only one that I find particularly evil.)</p>

<p>I responded to several ads in the craigslist "apartments for rent" section. One particular flavor of response stood out.</p>

<p>There were a lot of autoresponses from places with great, submarket rents, and they all ask you to fill out a rental application<strong> including a lot of personal information.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Responses were all from emails sent to listings where the original poster had used a public email address (as opposed to an anonymized craigslist address)</li>
    <li>Typical pattern is that someone lived in a gorgeous home, but had to go abroad.</li>
    <li>Abroad is typically West Africa, I have no idea why.</li>
    <li>Most of the respondents represent themselves as Christian (a reverand, a family doing missions in west africa, etc.)</li>
    <li>Tend to act as if they are aware you have the upper hand, but need to trust you (suddenly had to move away, need the money, willing to rent to you at a lower price if you're a good tenant, just prove it by emailing me your personal information). I think this is a play to disarm your suspicion.</li>
    <li>They generally display some sort of concern that they are going to be scammed themselves or a vulnerability that makes them want to qualify you as a tenant. For example, it is their personal family home, they have their furniture there and want to make sure it's in good hands in their absence.</li>
    <li>Prey on typical US perceptions of trustworthiness: Christians, ministers, reverends, families with young children</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Lessons learned:</strong>
Mostly spammers post "real" addresses. Real "real" people are afraid of posting their address in the open.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/b-e1339030520918-250x300.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-210" title="b" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/b-e1339030520918-250x300.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /></a></p>

<h2><strong>"Horny Young Co-Ed Wants To Chat"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA</strong> "Men Like Nude Women"
<strong>Actual Examples:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/adult.html">http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/adult.html</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Actually, I don't quite get this one. I assume the site somehow generates revenue from desperate men who want to hook up with hot sexy co-eds for free! (just enter your credit card! we won't use it! trust us!)</p>

<p>This is pretty interesting actually.</p>

<p>Mike gave a girl a copy of the Redeye, a daily pop culture/sports newspaperlet in Chicago.
He later posted in Missed Connections about it, and received a garbage reply:</p>

<p>Not thinking about it, he responded with a short one liner and unleashed upon himself the fury that is adult website spammers.</p>

<p>Every day since, he has received at least 1 unsolicited emails from different girls just trying to get him to sign up for a site to connect with hot girls like her that want to chat. The really amusing thing is that (1) many of these "different" girls somehow have the same picture, and (2) the emails are almost all identical. As a teaser, these girls all send nude pics of themselves, and amazingly, sometimes their nude pics don't even look like the same girl (weird, I know).</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Tries to act like a sexy coed who is afraid YOU are a scammer of some sort. She just wants to make sure she's not chatting with a "cam girl or a bot", which is clearly the spammers play to make you think *she* isn't a "cam girl or a bot"</li>
    <li>Clearly using an automated program to vary the text of the messages, probably as an attempt to avoid email spam filters</li>
    <li>Huge corpus of alternate urls for their site.</li>
    <li>All sent from different email addresses.</li>
    <li>Whose naked photos are these?!</li>
</ul>


<h2>"Spam" is not equal to "Scam"</h2>


<div><a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4079583">Callmeed on HN</a> made a point about distinguishing between "spam" and "scam".</div>


<div></div>


<div>The "Christian in West Africa Wants To Rent Lovely Home To You" category is the only one that I feel really bad about, because these people are screwing people over. The other ones are just companies doing some guerilla marketing. The "hot, horny women" category seems a little sleazy, and I don't actually know that they're NOT doing bad things with the data they collect (or what they collect), but on the surface it just seems like a spammy campaign to drive traffic.</div>


<h2>Common Characteristics in Many Craigslist Spam/Scam Messages</h2>


<ul>
    <li>Build rapport. Voice a common concern that you probably have to disqualify self as the threat.</li>
    <li>Act as an independent, concerned citizen. recommending a third party service.</li>
    <li>Respondents are female or generally prey on typical American stereotypes of honesty (Christian, African Foreign AID volunteer, social worker).</li>
    <li>Pose as vulnerable to empower the target</li>
    <li>Too good to be true</li>
</ul>


<p>The adult site one amuses me in particular because it is the most technically involved -- clearly using spinner code, likely for spam filter evasion; probably a script that autoregisters accounts with free services, so they might also have to be beating captchas; they are sending the largest total volume of email too, so they probably have to deal sending through lots of proxies to avoid getting blacklisted by the free mail services; tons of domains involved; and at the end of it, it seems like the least likely to get conversions.</p>

<p>Generally I think this stuff is pretty cool. With the exception of the spammers who pretend to give you rental applications, probably as a ploy to steal your identity, I consider these mostly just interesting "grey hat" marketing tactics.</p>

<p>Airbnb wasn't the only one. I imagine that there are probably even 3rd party "marketing companies" that do this for your startup.  I'd be interested in hearing more about it from the inside -- if you're reading this and you know someone who might be willing to talk to me, even anonymously, please connect me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
