<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-01T10:42:25-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Financing My Startup With My 401k]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/financing-my-startup-with-my-401k/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T09:01:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/financing-my-startup-with-my-401k</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As of one week ago, I am officially funding <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> with retirement fund money. This was not a decision made in haste. You may think I'm an idiot, and you may be right.</p>

<p><strong style="color:#D20606">This is a statement of fact documenting an action I took, not a "How To" document or a recommendation for anyone to do the same.</strong></p>

<h2>Retirement Money Isn't Sacred</h2>

<p>I am aware that many people consider 401k money off-limits. I consider it just another pool of capital with different access restrictions. I believe myself to be (mostly) rational in matters of risk/reward analysis especially pertaining to financial decisions.  Despite the obvious uncertainty in the future and the risk, I stand by this decision. Will it work out for me? Maybe not.</p>

<p>I am not interested in debating the merits of retirement savings and safety funds. Different people have different needs, desires, risk tolerances. This fit the bill for me. (Also, don't tell my mom. She falls on the side of safety, as mothers often do.)</p>

<p>I'll also say there was a weirdly sick exhiliration in cutting into my safety money to finance Rocket Lease. It made me realize:</p>

<ul>
<li>Yes, I'm dead serious about this.</li>
<li>Yes, I believe Rocket Lease will be a winner.</li>
<li>Yes, there are challenges ahead.</li>
<li>No, success is not certain.</li>
<li>Yes, I could fail and that would suck.</li>
</ul>


<p>The moment I got my check it suddenly became more real that I'm committed to the success of my current venture and that I will do whatever it takes to get to the finish line.</p>

<h2>Investing in Me</h2>

<p>This is, more than anything, an investment in myself.</p>

<p>I believe so strongly that dollars invested into Rocket Lease today can outperform <em>any</em> other investment that I have access to (admittedly not a lot of options... Weirdly, Jack Dorsey didn't call me for a check the last time Square closed a round).</p>

<p>Founders play "backseat founder" all the time, telling other startups what they should do. Fundamentally, this is a statement that the company being discussed has some deficiency that the speaker is somehow able to correct -- from the outside, with less information, via his/her brilliant insight.</p>

<p>This is a pervasive attribute of not only startup culture, but popular culture. What Romney could have done to win. What the CEO of ACME Widget Co should be doing. How other people can solve all their problems. Yelp would be better if. How Twitter could make a ton of money. This restaurant would be perfect if they just...</p>

<p><strong> Everyone other than you is doing it wrong. </strong></p>

<p>Yippee! I get to invest (even more) in me now. If this burns to the ground, it'll be on me.</p>

<p>Betting on yourself is great, because you can guarantee that the founder in your investment isn't spending his days on facebook or wasting time otherwise (well, sort of).</p>

<h2>There is No Free Lunch</h2>

<p>This is just the trader in me -- every transaction you make in life has risk and reward attached to it. Sushi or steak for dinner? Hire that growth hacker tomorrow or next month? For equity or cash?</p>

<p>I could have tried to raise a seed round. I could have sold equity to friends and family.  These avenues have all sorts of other hidden costs: loss of autonomy, investors to answer to, guilt at losing other people's money, the time/effort required to raise, etc.  The relative cost (penalties/fees) of the 401k path seemed more palatable to me in the long run.</p>

<p>Put it another way: Imagine you'll have to pay a 10% early distribution penalty and you only need ~40k.  How long does it take you to secure the financing and land the check from external investors, and how much equity do you give up.  Would be willing to pay 4k (10% early distribution penalty) to make all that effort disappear and retain total company equity? The answer to that question was yes for me, so I took an early distribution.</p>

<p>There are cheaper and more expensive transactions. 401k was the cheapest way for me to get what I wanted, and a great bet. I might lose it, but I'll be happy that I tried.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes from Noah Kagan talk at Chicago Growth Hackers Meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/notes-from-noah-kagan-talk-at-chicago-growth-hackers-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T22:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/notes-from-noah-kagan-talk-at-chicago-growth-hackers-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended a small event where Noah Kagan spoke to us about his experience and answered audience questions very candidly.</p>

<h2>Screw A/B testing, just build the product YOU would use</h2>

<p>I suspect it's a question of how much you let testing dictate strategy and user experience over personal preference. Nerds (including me) often think"data solves all". However, sometimes it comes at a user experience penalty and you can make the conscious decision to ignore it.For example, forcing users to input an email address to see the deal -- tests will show more signups, but users hate it. Same for how news sites paginate articles to optimize ad revenue. Balance your testing with a dose of "what user experience do YOU want?". Obviously split testing and analytics are still valuable. It's impossible to distill out the nuances of a founder's startup philosophy in a 10 minute segment.</p>

<h2>If you're not doing what you love, you're doing it wrong</h2>

<p>Noah genuinely believes in what he does. He got sick of building crappy facebook games, then payments for crappy facebook games. Do what you love (groundbreaking advice, I know).</p>

<p>related: <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2235-work-on-your-best-idea">37 Signals</a></p>

<h2>By the time you read about a distribution channel on a blog somewhere, the market is probably saturated</h2>

<p>Anything you read on a "growth hacking" blog is probably not the best way to get users (basically, fb ads have jumped the shark). If you want to get real growth, real fast, think outside the box.</p>

<h2>"Its easier to go deal drugs at other people's parties than make everyone come to your party."</h2>

<p>Partner with people who already have your customers. Many startups build a product and want it to be the destination site. Instead of trying to drive people to your site and convert users, go to the sites where your users are already hanging out and partner/advertise/guest blog, whatever.  My favorite quote of the night.</p>

<h2>Be aggressive</h2>

<p>Go to your competitors forums, facebook fan page, or whatever and start messaging their customers directly. I'm a fan of this sort of thing for early stage startups. HN pooped on <a href="http://www.virool.com/blog/how-to-land-fortune-100-brand-for-a-startup/">Virool's "crash your competitor panel" story</a> but I was a fan of that too.</p>

<h2>ONE METRIC</h2>

<p>Another one I liked. You need to have one metric that is paramount to all others. Knowing what SINGLE metric is your stated "most important metric" makes all decisions easy.  In the early days of Appsumo, this was "number of email addresses". If deciding between multiple courses of action, the winner was the answer to the question: "Which one is expected to move the needle on the stated metric more?" This one i liked.  Startup nerds overcomplicate stuff. This helps get you into "just fucking do it" mode.  Does it guarantee that you're chasing the RIGHT metric? no. Does it simplify decision making to get you information faster so you can change that metric later? probably. Everything you do should be in pursuit of moving the needle on this.</p>

<h2>When You Should Fire</h2>

<p>if an employee costs X to keep and delivers value less than X, they need to be canned. it's that easy. i enjoyed this comment, but i imagine that a lot of people think its too reductionist and dehumanizing. it resonates with me though, so i guess i'm just a robot.</p>

<h2>Other interesting bits</h2>

<ul>
<li>Appsumo sends 20million emails a month, and it costs $3500, using sendgrid</li>
<li>Appsumo did 3.5mm in revenue last year and are on pace for 7mm this year.</li>
<li>Noah says he would open a smoothie and taco stand if he wasn't doing appsumo and didn't have to work. i find this amusing.</li>
<li>I enjoyed his anecdote for how they came up with the name "appsumo".</li>
<li>Noah seems to be obsessed with tacos. he meditates 15 minutes a day. he has a scooter. he loves whole foods.</li>
<li>he made the comment that he's good at thinking 6 months ahead of the curve, but guys like Andrew Chen are great at thinking 18 months ahead.</li>
</ul>


<p>I mostly just wanted to see what Noah Kagan was like in person. I had heard mixed reports about his personality (funny, nice, abrasive, sexist, awkward) and wanted to experience the insanity first hand.</p>

<p>I'll admit there was the "I love reality TV" part of me that was hoping he'd say something ridiculous and sensationalist, but I can't say that he was anything other than very nice, charismatic, outgoing, well spoken, and not socially awkward at all.</p>

<p>There are no outsiders when Noah's around.  Noah is fantastic at making everyone feel like they're a part of the dialogue.  This is an amazing skill. If he's talking to a group of people and someone is on the outskirts, noah will politely interrupt the conversation, ask the circle to expand, and bring the outside person into the conversation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A/B Testing The Effect Of Sender Race On Email Response Rates]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/a-slash-b-testing-the-effect-of-sender-race-on-email-response-rates/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T21:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/a-slash-b-testing-the-effect-of-sender-race-on-email-response-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Are Emily and Brendan More Employable than Lakisha and Jamal?</h2>

<p>Issues of race and sex intrigue me.</p>

<p>Americans are very sensitive about discrimination (moreso than anywhere else in the world), it is generally taboo, and I believe Americans often bend over backwards to hide overt signs of racism and sexism in favor of subtle, but equally pernicious displays of masked discrimination.</p>

<p>I had heard of a well cited study (<a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/2100-201_162-575685.html">1</a>, <a href="http://www.nber.org/digest/sep03/w9873.html">2</a>, <a href="http://www.chicagobooth.edu/capideas/spring03/racialbias.html">3</a> <a href="http://faculty.chicagobooth.edu/marianne.bertrand/research/papers/emily_lakisha_aer.pdf">Original research</a>) indicating that employers respond more favorably to white names than black names. The study states that white names received 50% more responses than black names after sending out 5000 resumes.</p>

<p><strong>Question: How can I use societal prejudices to aid in startup success?</strong></p>

<h2>Race for Internet Marketing and Startups</h2>

<p>Imagine you intend to send an email to a prospective contact (PR, media, inquiring customer, totally unsolicited spam, whatever). You want the best possible response rate (opening your email, completing your survey). What if you could impact that just by controlling the "from" field on your outgoing email?</p>

<p>The implications of disparities in perceptions of race and gender extend beyond email marketing. How can you stack the odds in your favor for any human interaction?</p>

<p>Who should make your sales calls? Who should be the face of your company on TV? Do you need a <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-10-05/women-help-startups-succeed-dot-when-will-vcs-notice">woman as your CEO</a>? Startup success is hard earned, founders should take every advantage they can.</p>

<div class="note">
<p>One founder I know has a "hot girl networking strategy".</p>
<p>The basic idea is that if he wants to get in touch with an investor outside of his network, the best way to make that happen is through a warm intro from a portfolio company. He gets a hot girl to make the initial contact to a male founder in a portfolio company. If they connect to a male founder who gets excited by connecting with a hot girl, he might get the intro he wants.</p>
</div>


<h2>Experiment &amp; Findings</h2>

<p>I emailed around 1000000 people selling items on online classifieds sites from email addresses popularly associated with a specific race, then measured response rates for each race.</p>

<p>White names performed 11.9% better than black names (expected qualitative result, but less than the 50% disparity reported by the study)</p>

<p>Hipanic names performed 4.9% better than white names (surprising, statistically significant with 99.9% confidence)</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr><th>race</th><th>response rate</th></tr>
</thead>
<tr><td>black</td><td>11.01%</td></tr>
<tr><td>white</td><td>12.32%</td></tr>
<tr><td>hispanic</td><td>12.92%</td></tr>
</table>


<h2>Discussion</h2>

<p>I was unsurprised to find white names outperformed black names. I found it surprising that hispanic names outperformed both white and black names.</p>

<p><strong>White names outperformed black names by only 11.9% compared to the 50% in the employment study. Why?</strong></p>

<ol>
    <li>Different recipients - the original employer study targeted people making hiring decisions, this data targeted people selling things online.
        <ol style="list-style-type: upper-alpha;">
            <li>business owners/HR departments might be more racist,</li>
            <li>business owners/HR departments might have a different racial profile (is there a higher percentage of white small business owners than white "selling things online" people?),</li>
            <li>online sellers of goods might not care who they are selling to, they just want to move goods</li>
        </ol>
    </li>

    <li>Competing responses - in the original study, 4 resumes were sent to each employer, 2 white resumes and 2 black resumes. In our study, each recipient received only one inquiry and global response rates were measured. As such, the original study's resumes were in competition with one another.  If a white resume were selected, it could eliminate the possibility of response for a black resume, therefore exacerbating the disparity measured as a result of any racial bias.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Hispanic names outperformed white names.</strong></p>

<p>This was unexpected.  I expected whites to perform the best, but I had no evidence or knowledge of other studies to indicate that this ought to be the case.</p>

<p>The results measure the response rates from people who post items for sale on online classified ad sites. It would be interesting to see the racial breakdown for this posting population.</p>

<h2>Why I Did This</h2>

<p>My last startup, <a href="http://blog.ezliu.com/blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem/">Spaciety</a>, targeted a predominantly female population.</p>

<p>Like many startups, we wanted press and blog writeups. My cofounder AAD and I very unscientifically tested the effects of reaching out to blogs and spas using the same email, but from either one of our email accounts, or from the email account of a female intern.  In our unscientific, statistically insignificant exploration, we thought that the female sender garnered a much higher response rate.</p>

<p>I hoped to find evidence that a specific sender profile could help me get better response rates and media writeups.</p>

<p>We also collected data on open rates, gender, other races, posting section, subject lines and email body content.</p>

<h2>Method</h2>

<p>This section is boring, I encourage you to skip it.</p>

<ol>
<li>Create lists of names likely to be associated with only one race. To do so:<br />
<ol style="list-style-type:upper-roman;">
<li>Find publicly available lists of the most common given names by race.</li>
<li>Find publicly available lists of the most common surnames by race.</li>
<li>Remove any names that appear on more than one list.</li>
</ol>
<p>This leaves a list of surnames and given names that appear with high frequency in populations that have self-identified as belonging to a particular race.</p>

<li>Find email addresses in "items for sale" section of online classifieds websites.</li>
<li>For each such email address, randomly assign a "from" address on the email from a pool of names that occur with high frequency in either black, white, or hispanic children's names.</li>
<li>Email each address inquiring about the item for sale, originating from an email address with a name generated from a given name and surname from one of the lists as described above.</li>
<div class="note">
<p>For example, when emailing someone to inquire about an item for sale, randomly select between a black, white, or hispanic sender (say a random 3 sided die chose "hispanic"). Randomly select a given name from the hispanic given name list ("Antonio"). Randomly select a surname from the hispanic surname list ("Banderas"). Send an email from "Antonio Banderas" antonio.banderas@example.com.</p>
</div>
<li>For each email sent, embed a pixel to track open rates, and measure response rates by sender race.</li>
</ol>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chicago Coffee Shops: Where I Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T07:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/chicago-coffee-shops-where-i-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you're working on a startup or freelancing, you often find yourself frequenting cafes around town. If you're like me, you try to stay away from Starbucks.</p>

<p>I've compiled a list of personal favorites and recommendations from other startup friends, grouped by approximate geographic location.</p>

<p>If you're funemployed like me, have other great spots I can add to the list, or want to join the Chicago Daytime Coffeeshop Circuit, or "CDCC" as I like to call it (yep, I just made that up), drop a line: <a href="mailto:ezl@rocketlease.com">ipoopdaily@rocketlease.com</a></p>

<p>My personal favorites from below: Sip, Little Branch, Next Door Cafe, Wormhole, Floriole</p>

<h2>Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.pumproom.com/">Public Hotel</a> - Hotel lobby has a cafe in it with a huge work table. Work in luxurious surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://lmrestaurant.com/home.html">LM Bistro -- Hotel Felix bar</a> - I generally come here in the afternoons if I want to booze while I work. Great bourbon selection. Wifi: Free but spotty.</li>
<li><a href="http://wholefoodsmarket.com/stores/lincolnpark">Whole Foods North Ave</a> - Awesome. Huge work area on the second floor. Great food downstairs and a coffee bar. Also 6.00 bourbon pours and lots of great beer. Wifi: 2 hour limit, then just refresh your browser cookies; Huge plus == free parking.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/panera-bread-chicago-14">Panera @ Division/Sedgewick</a> - Eh, it's Panera. But you can park, so I come occasionally.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/starbucks-chicago-114">Starbucks Pipers Alley</a> - Eh, its starbucks, but its big so its easy to work with others here. Wifi its often brutal.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/ing-direct-cafe-chicago">ING Direct Cafe</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafedesarchitectes.com/">Cafe Des Architects</a> - Sofitel hotel restaurant - dead on weekdays and they're happy to have you just sit in. Gorgeous sunlit room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.delightfulpastries.com/">Delightful Pastries</a> - Lincoln park bakery, also dead on weekdays with nice staff. Tea isn't cheap: $4.38. Pastries are cloyingly sweet. But 4.38 to rent an office for the afternoon works for me.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/elaines-coffee-call-chicago">Elaines Coffee Call</a> - Very cute spot in the Lincoln Hotel. Great almond milk latte.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/evas-cafe-chicago-2">Evas</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Near But Not As Near North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.uncommonground.com/">Uncommon Ground</a> - Only been to the Wrigleyville one. Nice big windows to let in the sun.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nextdoorchi.com/">Next Door Cafe</a> - Lets you book conference rooms for free, great restaurants nearby, and if you're feeling adventurous, you can park at Trader Joe's next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.floriole.com/">Floriole</a> - Best pastries in the city. Wifi is usually good. Staff is generally nice, but J can get a little snarky if he thinks you're sitting there too long.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thebourgeoispigcafe.com/">The Bourgeois Pig</a> - Classic spot, old two story house. Can get crowded.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.citygroundschicago.com/">Citygrounds</a> - Typically a good hideaway that stays pretty quiet, even on weekends.</li>
<li><a href="http://bowtruss.com/">Bow Truss</a> - Terrible spot to work, they're really a roaster. No idea why I'm leaving this on the list. Very sexy website though.</li>
<li><a href="http://kickstandcoffee.com/">Kickstand</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.coffeeandtea.com/">Coffee and Tea</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Even More North</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/kopi-travelers-cafe-chicago">Kopi Travelers</a> - No Wifi, but i REALLY dig the atmosphere here. Get one of the spots by the window entrance its like a hippie Japanese tatami room.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thecoffeestudio.com/">Coffee Studio</a> - Modern minimalist coffee shop with great espresso. Unforunately it often packs out.</li>
<li><a href="http://chavacafe.com/">Chava</a> - I think this place was supposed to be a Starbucks, but then corporate backed out. Chava got a great, built out spot.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bookcellarinc.com/cafe">Book Cellar</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.asadocoffee.com/">Asado</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dollopcoffee.com/">Dollop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/julius-meinl-chicago-2">Julius Meinl</a> - Packs out. Nice pastries</li>
</ul>


<h2>So Far North It Might As Well Be Wisconsin</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.metropoliscoffee.com/">Metropolis</a> - Too far away, but if you're in this hood, a good work spot.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Near West</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/sip-coffee-house-and-garden-chicago">Sip</a> - Personal favorite. This is in my top 3. Cheap tea, cool staff, awesome vibe. Park on Hubbard.</li>
<li><a href="http://swimcafe.com/">Swim Cafe</a> - Big open room can get cold and loud. Good food though. Can typically find parking in front of the school next door.</li>
<li><a href="http://bigshoulderscoffee.com/">Big Shoulders Coffee</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.lovelybakeshop.com/home.php">Lovely</a> - Kind of a weird spot, its typically second place if swim is full.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/letizias-natural-bakery-chicago">Letizia's Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jupiteroutpost.com/">Jupiter Outpost</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Old HipsterVille South (Wicker/Ukranian Village-ish)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Atomix-Coffee-Shop/83455341497">Atomix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cafeballouchicago.com/">Cafe Ballou</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.knockboxcafe.com/">Knockbox</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.alliance-bakery.com/">Alliance Bakery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.prasino.com/locations_chicago.html">Prasino</a> - Don't go on weekends, you'll be stepping on their lunch service, but during the week its wide open.  A little smug, but I love the big windows.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffestreets.com/">Caffe Streets</a> - I think this place gets too loud, but my friends dig it.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Old Hipsterville North (Bucktown)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://thewormhole.us/">Wormhole</a> - They have an old school Nintendo. That is all that matters.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/filter-chicago">Filter</a> - Spotty. Go to Wormhole.</li>
<li><a href="http://caffedeluca.com/">Caffe Deluca</a> - Not really the best work spot, but you can camp out for 2 hours or so and get great food.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.redjunecafe.com/">Red June</a> - Great all day work spot, but not the "warmest" surroundings.</li>
<li><a href="http://bonbonsandwiches.com/">Bon Bon</a> - Eclectic decor, free wifi, great Vietnamese sandwiches. Proprieter, Tim, is a nice dude.</li>
</ul>


<h2>South</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.artists-cafe.com/">Artists Cafe</a> -- Conveniently near MT's house or I wouldn't ever go.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.littlebranchcafe.com/">Little Branch</a> -- Even more convenient so this is pretty much the only South Loop spot I hit.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.overflowcoffeebar.org/">Overflow</a> -- Weirdly barren.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.efebinascafe.com/">Efebina's</a> -- Decent spot if you're close to Chinatown</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/cafe-jumping-bean-chicago">Jumping Bean</a> -- Not that great, but the only thing I know of near Honky Tonk BBQ.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bridgeportcoffeecompany.com/">Bridgeport Coffee Company</a> -- Good spot, street parking, but not worth the trek for me.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
