<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TV | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/tv/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-30T16:34:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
