<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: spaciety | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/spaciety/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T11:47:10-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A/B Testing The Effect Of Sender Race On Email Response Rates]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/a-slash-b-testing-the-effect-of-sender-race-on-email-response-rates/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T21:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/a-slash-b-testing-the-effect-of-sender-race-on-email-response-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Are Emily and Brendan More Employable than Lakisha and Jamal?</h2>

<p>Issues of race and sex intrigue me.</p>

<p>Americans are very sensitive about discrimination (moreso than anywhere else in the world), it is generally taboo, and I believe Americans often bend over backwards to hide overt signs of racism and sexism in favor of subtle, but equally pernicious displays of masked discrimination.</p>

<p>I had heard of a well cited study (<a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/2100-201_162-575685.html">1</a>, <a href="http://www.nber.org/digest/sep03/w9873.html">2</a>, <a href="http://www.chicagobooth.edu/capideas/spring03/racialbias.html">3</a> <a href="http://faculty.chicagobooth.edu/marianne.bertrand/research/papers/emily_lakisha_aer.pdf">Original research</a>) indicating that employers respond more favorably to white names than black names. The study states that white names received 50% more responses than black names after sending out 5000 resumes.</p>

<p><strong>Question: How can I use societal prejudices to aid in startup success?</strong></p>

<h2>Race for Internet Marketing and Startups</h2>

<p>Imagine you intend to send an email to a prospective contact (PR, media, inquiring customer, totally unsolicited spam, whatever). You want the best possible response rate (opening your email, completing your survey). What if you could impact that just by controlling the "from" field on your outgoing email?</p>

<p>The implications of disparities in perceptions of race and gender extend beyond email marketing. How can you stack the odds in your favor for any human interaction?</p>

<p>Who should make your sales calls? Who should be the face of your company on TV? Do you need a <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-10-05/women-help-startups-succeed-dot-when-will-vcs-notice">woman as your CEO</a>? Startup success is hard earned, founders should take every advantage they can.</p>

<div class="note">
<p>One founder I know has a "hot girl networking strategy".</p>
<p>The basic idea is that if he wants to get in touch with an investor outside of his network, the best way to make that happen is through a warm intro from a portfolio company. He gets a hot girl to make the initial contact to a male founder in a portfolio company. If they connect to a male founder who gets excited by connecting with a hot girl, he might get the intro he wants.</p>
</div>


<h2>Experiment &amp; Findings</h2>

<p>I emailed around 1000000 people selling items on online classifieds sites from email addresses popularly associated with a specific race, then measured response rates for each race.</p>

<p>White names performed 11.9% better than black names (expected qualitative result, but less than the 50% disparity reported by the study)</p>

<p>Hipanic names performed 4.9% better than white names (surprising, statistically significant with 99.9% confidence)</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr><th>race</th><th>response rate</th></tr>
</thead>
<tr><td>black</td><td>11.01%</td></tr>
<tr><td>white</td><td>12.32%</td></tr>
<tr><td>hispanic</td><td>12.92%</td></tr>
</table>


<h2>Discussion</h2>

<p>I was unsurprised to find white names outperformed black names. I found it surprising that hispanic names outperformed both white and black names.</p>

<p><strong>White names outperformed black names by only 11.9% compared to the 50% in the employment study. Why?</strong></p>

<ol>
    <li>Different recipients - the original employer study targeted people making hiring decisions, this data targeted people selling things online.
        <ol style="list-style-type: upper-alpha;">
            <li>business owners/HR departments might be more racist,</li>
            <li>business owners/HR departments might have a different racial profile (is there a higher percentage of white small business owners than white "selling things online" people?),</li>
            <li>online sellers of goods might not care who they are selling to, they just want to move goods</li>
        </ol>
    </li>

    <li>Competing responses - in the original study, 4 resumes were sent to each employer, 2 white resumes and 2 black resumes. In our study, each recipient received only one inquiry and global response rates were measured. As such, the original study's resumes were in competition with one another.  If a white resume were selected, it could eliminate the possibility of response for a black resume, therefore exacerbating the disparity measured as a result of any racial bias.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Hispanic names outperformed white names.</strong></p>

<p>This was unexpected.  I expected whites to perform the best, but I had no evidence or knowledge of other studies to indicate that this ought to be the case.</p>

<p>The results measure the response rates from people who post items for sale on online classified ad sites. It would be interesting to see the racial breakdown for this posting population.</p>

<h2>Why I Did This</h2>

<p>My last startup, <a href="http://blog.ezliu.com/blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem/">Spaciety</a>, targeted a predominantly female population.</p>

<p>Like many startups, we wanted press and blog writeups. My cofounder AAD and I very unscientifically tested the effects of reaching out to blogs and spas using the same email, but from either one of our email accounts, or from the email account of a female intern.  In our unscientific, statistically insignificant exploration, we thought that the female sender garnered a much higher response rate.</p>

<p>I hoped to find evidence that a specific sender profile could help me get better response rates and media writeups.</p>

<p>We also collected data on open rates, gender, other races, posting section, subject lines and email body content.</p>

<h2>Method</h2>

<p>This section is boring, I encourage you to skip it.</p>

<ol>
<li>Create lists of names likely to be associated with only one race. To do so:<br />
<ol style="list-style-type:upper-roman;">
<li>Find publicly available lists of the most common given names by race.</li>
<li>Find publicly available lists of the most common surnames by race.</li>
<li>Remove any names that appear on more than one list.</li>
</ol>
<p>This leaves a list of surnames and given names that appear with high frequency in populations that have self-identified as belonging to a particular race.</p>

<li>Find email addresses in "items for sale" section of online classifieds websites.</li>
<li>For each such email address, randomly assign a "from" address on the email from a pool of names that occur with high frequency in either black, white, or hispanic children's names.</li>
<li>Email each address inquiring about the item for sale, originating from an email address with a name generated from a given name and surname from one of the lists as described above.</li>
<div class="note">
<p>For example, when emailing someone to inquire about an item for sale, randomly select between a black, white, or hispanic sender (say a random 3 sided die chose "hispanic"). Randomly select a given name from the hispanic given name list ("Antonio"). Randomly select a surname from the hispanic surname list ("Banderas"). Send an email from "Antonio Banderas" antonio.banderas@example.com.</p>
</div>
<li>For each email sent, embed a pixel to track open rates, and measure response rates by sender race.</li>
</ol>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death of a Startup: Spaciety Post-mortem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/death-of-a-startup-spaciety-post-mortem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Background</h2>


<p>For those in catchup mode, until recently I was working on a startup called Spaciety (Pronounced: SPA-siety, like combining the words SPA &amp; soCIETY. That seemed really clever until we realized nobody could figure it out.  Startup rule #1: Avoid pronunciation ambiguity).</p>


<p><span>Spaciety is dead and we killed it</span>.  AAD, JBV, and I all invested a lot of effort into Spaciety, and we ultimately folded.</p>


<p><span><strong>Spaciety is Open Table or Expedia for spas and salons. We made it easy for customers to search for and book beauty services online</strong>.</span>  I&#8217;ll save most of the sales pitch for below, but spas and salons are a $100+ billion industry that is very fragmented and poorly served by technology.  It&#8217;s a very exciting space and someone will come make a killing, but it won&#8217;t be us.</p>


<p>Startup death is part of the game, and we knew we&#8217;d have to quit if it was a dud. The hard part was killing it when we might have had something good.</p>


<h2>Why Spaciety was / is great</h2>


<p><strong>Spaciety had over 100 partner spas listing services on the website at the time we made the decision to shut it down.  Spas love the idea.</strong></p>


<p>The spa industry as a whole has a vacancy rate somewhere north of 40%.  This poses a problem for spas since their &#8220;inventory&#8221; effectively self-destructs every hour.  If you have no massage bookings today, you can&#8217;t just book twice as many massages tomorrow to cover the loss.  As a result, spas are actually quite eager to sign up with a service that helps them book off-peak hours, even at substantial discounts.</p>


<p>The real value was in providing <span><strong>variable, occupancy-based pricing</strong> model</span> that allowed spas to keep peak hours at standard rates, but progressively lower rates for off-peak hours (fancytalk for &#8220;as spa owners get more desperate&#8221;). Remember: one minute before 2pm on a Wednesday, the spa has effectively agreed to accept $0 revenue for each unbooked appointment. Spaciety sold the ability to reach an audience willing to pay more than $0 at the last minute, and that was a powerful thing.</p>


<p>This is contrary to Groupon&#8217;s or Living Social&#8217;s model where spas offer large discounts, but those coupons often go towards filling up peak hours when the spa would have been booked anyways. This hurts spa owners because they accept less revenue where they would normally make money to cover down times.  There are so many daily deal sites offering spa services that these dealhunters rarely come back and there is very little positive impact in off-peak booking rates.</p>


<p>Basically, <strong>spas wanted to use it &amp; customers were ecstatic</strong> about being able to book online.</p>


<h2>Then Spaciety said &#8220;Let there be online booking&#8221;, and there was online booking</h2>


<p>Unfortunately, I can&#8217;t claim credit for the initial build &#8212; the <strong>real stars are AAD and JBV</strong>. They were very proactive, talked to spa owners, got feedback, collaborated closely with a <a href="http://pybrew.com" target="_blank">crack team of developers</a> to build a working solution, and got the business off the ground.  They pounded pavement, called spas, <strong>flirted with spa owners</strong> (both  female and male&#8230; it was ugly&#8230;), and otherwise did whatever they had to do to sign people up.</p>


<p>I was treading water on my own startup at the time and they were minting revenue in the first week of launch. I certainly eyed their success with envy.</p>


<p>For my friends who aren&#8217;t startup people: <strong>the idea always sounds easy</strong>, but execution&#8217;s a bitch. Web startups don&#8217;t cost money to build, they cost blood, sweat, and tears. <strong>Making that first dollar is damn near impossible</strong>.  Mad props, gents.  AAD and JBV rose to the challenge and then some.  When they later invited me to officially join the team, I could not have felt more honored.</p>


<h2>Fatal flaw</h2>


<p>After the crushingly successful launch, there was an experimentation period where we tried various strategies to grow.  There&#8217;s a myth that startups follow some sort of exponential growth path (It&#8217;s just that &#8212; a myth).  The trajectory for Spaciety was more like a series of plateaus.  We took a very methodical approach to testing and measuring new strategies for growth, but we kept flatlining.  Despite this, we continued to grow both the consumer and spa sides of the business until it became clear that we would have problems scaling the business in its current form.</p>


<p>The <strong>initial plan for Spaciety was to tightly integrate with each spa&#8217;s appointment booking software</strong> and algorithmically determine optimal pricing for each appointment.  What we found was that there is no universal schedling software, or even a clear market leader.  Most booking systems don&#8217;t have easy ways to extract the data, the market is highly fragmented, there&#8217;s no dominant technology, no standard data format, adoption is highly regional, and the systems are old &#8212; &#8220;built in the early 90s&#8221; old (techsnob speak for &#8220;unusable/ancient&#8221;).</p>


<p>As an alternative, Spaciety worked with individual spas to determine what appointments were generally unbooked from week to week and listed those appointments on the site. <span><strong>Whenever an appointment was booked online, our automated system would call the spa to confirm availability</strong></span> (&#8220;If this appointment is available, press 1; if not, press 9&#8221;). The Spaciety site inventory represented a <strong>highly probable, but not guaranteed inventory</strong>, as determined based on the historical bookings of a particular spa.</p>


<p>As a result, there was<span> always some <strong>chance that a customer would book an appointment and it would be unavailable</strong></span>.  To mitigate this issue, we 1) concentrated on acquiring multiple spas in close proximity so we could direct overflow to nearby partner spas, 2) made sure spas were aware of this so they would try to be flexible squeezing in appointments for us.</p>


<p>This worked well for a while, but somewhere around 85 partner spas, AAD started spending an inordinate amount of time/effort dealing with unavailable appointments.  <strong>85 spas worth of listings, each with a small chance of being unavailable added up to a big chance of problems on any given day</strong>.  Dealing with these collisions takes more time than you&#8217;d think, and the fear that it could happen at any time worried us constantly.</p>


<p><strong>As we continued to grow, it was clear that this strategy was unsustainable.</strong></p>


<h2>Darkness</h2>


<p>It&#8217;s really frustrating to work hard, get something to start working, and only then realize that you&#8217;re tanked. </p>


<p>Imagine standing at the bottom of a deep well with fog overhead. You can&#8217;t see the top. There are 20 ladders going up, but you can&#8217;t see how high they go.  We had just climbed one of the ladders and found out that it stopped dead 30 feet up.</p>


<p>When you climb back down and look around at the other 19 ladders around you, not knowing (1) how high each will take you, or (2) <em><strong>if any of them even get to the top</strong></em>, it&#8217;s scary.  <strong>It&#8217;s demoralizing</strong>.  And we were somewhere around ladder #5 by this point.</p>


<h2>Light</h2>


<p>It was clear to us that we needed to bite the bullet and <strong>explore full integration with all the Spa Scheduling Software Systems</strong> (S4, yeah thats right, I just made up that acronym).  What we found that was that there were way <span>too many systems and almost all of them were outdated</span>.</p>


<p>We had 2 options:</p>


<ol><li><strong>Building and maintaining X packages</strong> to integrate with all the software systems</li>
<li><strong>Building our own scheduling system </strong>and defining and publishing a standard for the industry to use for appointment information (hotel industry has something similar)</li>
</ol>


<p>We quickly eliminated Option A &#8212; we didn&#8217;t want to go from &#8220;guys who are revolutionizing the spa industry&#8221; to &#8220;guys who maintain 50 different software integration modules and whose software breaks anytime an independent vendor changes their code&#8221;. And it sounded boring.</p>


<p>Option B is surprisingly compelling.  The idea was that we could <strong>leverage our existing trust with in-network spas</strong> to develop better software (we&#8217;re good at developing good software, fast) and <strong>immediately have it in a large number of spas</strong>.</p>


<p>We spoke with a lot of people about this and we settled on <span>building and <strong>distributing the software for free, then using it as a funnel for taking transaction fees</strong> on online bookings</span>.  &#8221;Owning&#8221; the centralized source of all appointment data is wildly valuable for all sorts of reasons.</p>


<p>Additionally, investors who were already interested in us really perked up because building the software and owning the data gave us<strong> defensible IP and increased barriers to entry</strong> for direct competitors.  We already understood the market, had the trust of spa owners, and know how to build next generation software.</p>


<p>We accidentally stumbled upon <strong>something investors liked more</strong>.  We flirted with funds. Contacts from our old finance careers were asking to give us money.  We literally just had to sign on the dotted line to get funding.</p>


<p>One problem: <strong>It&#8217;s a long game</strong>.  Even if we got into 100 spas today, we needed to get into 5,000 spas.  Building good software isn&#8217;t enough for that. <strong>We&#8217;d be committing to building and selling for 2 years to even find out if we had a fighting shot</strong>.</p>


<p>In the end, <span>it was another ladder into the fog</span>. We didn&#8217;t want to risk ending at the top of a really high ladder in 2 years.  If we had started this path 2 years ago, I might be writing a different story. But our lives had changed in the last 2 years (AAD, congrats on the new baby!) and the risk/reward profile of the new path no longer fit our current desires.  </p>


<p>The work would be long, the path uncertain, and the payout questionable.  Those are always true, but we were looking for something that was either more likely, less difficult, or testable on a shorter time horizon. The business profile just wasn&#8217;t right for us.</p>


<h2>Founder-startup fit</h2>


<p>Startup people spend a lot of time talking about &#8220;product-market fit&#8221;, meaning &#8220;do you have a product the market wants?&#8221; But sometimes the product-market fit is right, but the founders don&#8217;t fit the startup. When I was 23 with $475 rent, I would have run for a 2% chance at 100mm, but old man me prefers a 50% chance at 3mm. Spaciety died because the business model it forced wasn&#8217;t right for us.</p>


<p>I wonder how many startups die because of founder-startup fit. Or how many founders don&#8217;t recognize the lack of founder-startup fit and ride a trajectory to failure. The truth is, I think AAD and I were blessed with great mentors and friends; we were lucky to be able to assess the lack of fit and make the hard, but rational call to shut it down.</p>


<p>Like all stories, there&#8217;s more complexity to this one, but if you want to hear about it you&#8217;ll have to sit the 3 of us down for a drink. On you. Preferably something very expensive.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
