<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rocketlease | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/rocketlease/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-30T16:32:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Hire Salespeople For A Startup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/how-to-hire-salespeople-for-a-startup/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T10:28:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/how-to-hire-salespeople-for-a-startup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Before You Post Your Ad</h2>

<h3>Don't be afraid to spend 25 bucks on a job post</h3>

<p>Say what you will about Craigslist, it's still where everyone goes to find jobs.
It costs $25 to post in the jobs section. You can post in the gigs section for free. If you're not ready to invest $25 to get better candidates,
you're not ready to invest in a salesperson.</p>

<h3>Don't make it too easy</h3>

<p>Don't give them all the information they need. Make them hunt through your website for
your contact info. Or linked in. Make your information available, but not obvious. This will weed out people who are just mass mailing
resumes.</p>

<h3>Set up phone interviews</h3>

<p>Set up a phone interview for some time in the future. Give them 2 options, and ask them to pick one that works for them. Have them call you
at the stated time. You are looking for: (a) a confirmation email "yes, i'll call you at time X", and (b) that they actually call on time.</p>

<p>These are important because they weed out (a) people who can't communicate clearly about future events/expectations and (b) candidates who
are unreliable or can't manage their calendar [managing future calls is important for followups to prospects]</p>

<h3>The interview starts when they contact you first</h3>

<p>Typos in emails, an inability to communicate effectively via email, unreliable, missed phone calls, are all reasons to end the process.
There are lots of fantastic salespeople out there, don't settle for those with obvious deficits.</p>

<h2>The Phone Interview</h2>

<h3>If you aren't convinced by the interview, prospects won't be convinced by their sales pitch</h3>

<p>The phone interview is a sales call where the salesperson is selling himself to you.
Is he smooth on the phone, does he guide the conversation, does he ask good questions, is
he personable, do you like him?</p>

<ul>
<li>Do they ramble? If they do, let them go. See how long it goes. Sales isn't about the salesperson, it's about the prospect. Talking forever about themselves is a negative indicator.</li>
<li>If the conversation stops, do NOT fill the space for them -- see what they do with the awkward silence.</li>
<li>Do they overuse filler words like "um" and "like"? You want someone that sounds smooth, assertive, and confident. If they don't sound professional and convincing in an interview, they won't when they sell your product.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Great candidates will ask you questions about the role, what you need, and tell you if it's a good fit.</h3>

<p>Awesomeness doesn't happen in a vacuum. You don't want a candidate who is just awesome alone --
he/she has to be awesome with your product.</p>

<p>Do they tell stories about themselves like they're trying too hard to sell themselves? Great sales
is about finding <strong>FIT</strong>, not talking about how AWESOME your product is.  They should be asking about
your NEEDS and seeing how they can fill them.  They should be asking a lot of questions, not regaling
you with stories of how much revenue they closed in an unrelated industry.</p>

<p><strong>There's no perfect salesperson and there's no perfect product.</strong></p>

<p>The salesperson's job is to find out the prospect's needs/pain points, then show how your product
can solve that. If he's not looking for fit between him and you, he won't be looking for fit between
your product and your customers.</p>

<h3>What sorts of things can't you sell / What was the hardest thing you've ever had to sell?</h3>

<p>Salespeople love to say they can sell anything. That's never true. Some products
are too expensive, or don't have product-market fit, or just plain suck.  Ask what they struggled to sell or
what sorts of products they think they wouldn't be able to sell. If the answer is "nothing", it indicates
either delusion or an inability to reason.</p>

<h3>Metrics</h3>

<p>Ask them what sorts of metrics they track and how they track them.  Calls, decision makers, demos, etc.
How do they typically gauge success?</p>

<p>Also, what system do they use for tracking it (assuming you don't already
have this stuff in place).  As a founder, your job isn't to train people to sell. You want people who
already think about this the right way. You need metrics, and good salespeople will have answers for you.</p>

<h3>Do they set a time to follow up?</h3>

<p><strong>This is important.</strong></p>

<p>Wind down the interview in typical fashion. Thank them for their time. Don't offer any future plans. Refrain from
saying "ok, if i'm interested, i'll get back to you next week" or something like that. Just thank them.</p>

<p>A salesperson's
job is to make sales. But many products require multiple touchpoints with busy people. Your salesperson needs to
be effective at getting to the next step.</p>

<p>Salespeople can waste a
lot of time chasing dead leads that aren't interested.  To be efficient, they need to be able to identify which leads
are dead and prune them. At the end of any sales call, they should be either:</p>

<ul>
<li>(a) realizing that the lead is no good, or</li>
<li>(b) scheduling a specific follow up time</li>
</ul>


<p>If they don't either (a) try to eliminate themselves from the running, or (b) nail you down to a specific future time,
won't do that with prospects.</p>

<p>Great questions:</p>

<ul>
<li>"What are you looking for in order to make a decision"</li>
<li>"What could make you decide to either hire me or eliminate me as a candidate right now?"</li>
<li>"In what timeframe do you intend to make a decision"</li>
<li>"OK, so if I don't hear from you by Friday, would it be ok for me to reach out to you on Monday to follow up?"</li>
</ul>


<p>The result of this is that they'll be forced to follow up in the future. See if they do.
If they can't get their calendar together for a job, they'll fail with prospects.</p>

<h2>Other thoughts</h2>

<h3>Typing speed</h3>

<p>This is usually a pretty good indicator of computer usage and that's important to me:</p>

<ul>
<li>I do screensharing demos for Rocket Lease. A prospect gets bored watching you slowly type in a bunch of fields on a form.</li>
<li>I communicate via email. If written text is important for you to communicate, you probably type reasonably fast as well.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Hotmail accounts</h3>

<p>This is a bad filter, and I don't recommend it for everyone, but if you're writing me from a hotmail
account, wtf? Who uses that anymore?</p>

<p>I sell a tech product, and most people who live on the internet don't use hotmail anymore.</p>

<h3>Ask your interviewee what you should be looking for</h3>

<p>You want candidates who are realistic, and can make decisions on behalf of your company. Ask the candidate
what he/she thinks you should be looking for in a hire. Basically, put him/her in the interviewer's shoes.</p>

<p>Great candidates are comfortable stepping outside of the interviewee role and giving answers that aren't
just "pick me, pick me!"</p>

<h3>Try to talk them out of the job (thanks TG)</h3>

<p><em>"This job isn't for everyone... Well, we're a startup, and so a lot of times that means it's not very structured... some
people hate that... you may be able to make more money in the short term somewhere else..."</em></p>

<p>You're not trying to scare them off, but this will help bring out some of the real issues with the job, their requirements,
and determine if it's really a fit.</p>

<p>This might seem like you're scaring away good candidates, but if you start down a path with someone where it's not a fit,
you'll be wasting your own time and resources, so you'd rather filter aggressively and be left with more high probability candidates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocket Lease 2012: What Worked, What Didn't, What's Next]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/rocket-lease-2012-what-worked/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T13:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/rocket-lease-2012-what-worked</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> makes it easy for landlords to use an online application to screen prospective tenants. It automatically runs credit reports, background checks, and eviction histories, saving the property manager time and money. I believe so strongly in the product that I left my career as an overpaid options trader and to the point where I've <a href="http://blog.ezliu.com/blog/financing-my-startup-with-my-401k/">invested money from my retirement funds</a> into the venture.</p>

<p>I started working on Rocket Lease full time in Dec 2011 and publicly launched in May 2012. It has been my fulltime pursuit since. I am confident (perhaps delusional) that this is the best startup idea I've worked on to date and that my effort will ultimately be rewarded.</p>

<p>However, the journey hasn't been without trials, so this is a short note chronicling the successes and failures to date.</p>

<h2>Things That Worked</h2>

<h3>Talked to a lot of customers before I building</h3>

<p>I worked with property managers and leasing agents to draw wireframes, describe the process and workflow. I did this at bars, coffee shops, and while working out of their offices alongside them.  This was important for me to create the right product for my customers.  One caveat is that I wasn't aggressive enough about defining the truly MINIMUM viable product, so as a result of talking to many people, I ended up building in more features than necessary and spending more time than I had to on my MVP.</p>

<h3>Spend money on the startup</h3>

<p>It was easy for me in the past to try to build everything (there's no better price than free!) and end up wasting a lot of time.  On Rocket Lease, I took the opposite approach, where I almost always try to find some way to NOT build something in house.  Same thing goes for services -- instead of looking for free services or straining to say on a free plan in a Freemium or SAAS offering, if what I need costs money, just pay it. Some services that have made my life better: codebasehq.com, linode, mailchimp, sanebox, hipchat, idonethis, twilio, skype.</p>

<h3>Spend money on me</h3>

<p>In previous startups, I had taken the approach that I'm cash strapped, so I had to <em>act</em> cash strapped. Don't go out, don't see friends, work all the time.  You probably already know this story ends in me burning out.  While I still work on Rocket Lease 7 days a week and think about it 25 hours a day, I'm unapologetic about carving out personal time and enjoying sushi.  I suspect, though can't prove, that it's made me more productive overall.</p>

<h3>Outsource</h3>

<p>My to do list is a mile long, and a lot of those tasks are outsourceable.  I have found a fantastic blog writer (thanks Jake) who helps me manage content creation, I've outsourced SEO consulting and execution, VA tasks like compiling lists of property managers, sending emails to investors, making sales phone calls, picking up dry cleaning, creating twitter accounts (yep, tons of em) and sending boxes of chocolate to customers.  My biggest single outsourcing expense is programming now. I initially wrote a lot of the code, the first version was built entirely by me, but I've since reduced my code contribution to &lt; 20%.  I still help architect, discuss and evaluate code, but I now focus almost entirely on how to get traction.  Henrique isn't just a hired gun, he's a CTO for hire, a trusted and valued asset, and Rocket Lease wouldn't be possible without him.</p>

<p>I've spent a lot on outsourcing, but my quality of life is definitely better as a result.</p>

<h3>Interns</h3>

<p>I experimented with interns this summer.  What I will say about interns is that I'm glad I did it, and there were a lot of great things that came of it, but it was largely inefficient for me.  My interns were all really awesome, highly intelligent, but it's impossible to expect anyone to have the same level of fanaticism about your startup that you do.  Also, this isn't a knock on interns -- it's always hard to find good PEOPLE, whether interns, full-time, paid or unpaid. In that regard I was lucky that Mike found the highest quality people to work with.  It was a good experience for me, I spent a lot of time, got more frustrated than I should have, but also learned a lot about managing people (and about my desire to manage people going forward).</p>

<h2>Things that didn't work</h2>

<h3>SEO</h3>

<p>I suck at this. I spent an inordinate amount of effort early on trying to rank for keywords that I thought were valuable.  Unfortuantely, the reality is that people don't search for online apartments application solutions. They search for apartments.  And these folks are tenants, who are NOT Rocket Lease's primary customer.</p>

<p>Anyone who is already renting apartments (my target customers) already has <em>A</em> solution in place that works.  The only time they start looking is when their existing solution breaks. And even then they might not turn to Google.</p>

<p>I don't want to knock this entirely, because we've done very well with words that we wanted to rank for, and over 70% of our revenue last year came from customers who found us via Google. But they are relatively low volume keywords, so I think we're tapped out on the total amount of traffic we can drive through the existing keywords we targeted.  The next tier of keywords up that we'd LOVE to rank for seem way out of reach though, so I'm hesitant to expend more effort chasing HUGE keywords.</p>

<h3>Adwords</h3>

<p>I suck at this too. I wrote about my experience with Adwords <a href="http://blog.ezliu.com/blog/currently-paying-150-per-conversion/">here</a>. Fundamentally, I think the real problem here is that not enough apartment owners and landlords are LOOKING for rental application solutions.  Arguably I should just keep this going though since I think it can be cost effective, but optimizing the campaign was a lot of work, and at the time it was unclear whether or not it <em>would</em> pay off.  Unfortunately also, since the search volume for high converting keywords is low, it seems like it would take a long time to optimize the effort to pay off.  Also, the high converting keywords seem in striking range for organic search rankings.</p>

<h3>Reddit</h3>

<p>I ran ads on reddit. I wasn't trying to recruit users though, I was trying to recruit evangelists.</p>

<p>I was very explicit and the ad copy was basically "I need your help, Reddit". I briefly explained what Rocket Lease was, how I think it's insane that 88% of rental applications are still processed on paper, and made it easy for redditors to send an email to their landlord.</p>

<p>I didn't have much to offer to incentivize Redditors to help me in the cause (I could have done some sort of reward, but Redditors are smarter than that and see through stuff like that).  Redditors have a high concentration of renters who would rather fill out electronic forms than paper. Part of me was hoping that would be enough of an appeal to help me kill the paper application. It wasn't. But the campaign was cheap and fast so no regrets.</p>

<h3>Contest</h3>

<p>I created "win a free month of rent" contest (capped at $1500 bucks, sorry Manhattan). My target customer is the landlord, but my goal was to reach a huge number of renters and convince them to sell to their landlords. Fundamentally, it was just a lottery: "give me your email for an entry in the drawing".</p>

<p>The bit of cleverness (if I do say so) was that the contest encouraged growth by making it incredibly easy for people to share on FB or twitter, then gave more entries into the contest if (a) they shared, (b) anyone signed up through their fb or twitter updates.  I split tested: just twitter, just facebook, multiple fb options (messaging friends, status update, liking page), and a bunch of other combinations to see how I could maximize collection of emails.</p>

<p>Additionally, there was a customer.io lifecycle email campaign tied to the backend that would notify users whenever someone signed up through one of their links (to encourage them to come back) and mailchimp drip campaign tied to the backend of this that would let them know more about Rocket Lease and also give them tips on how else to share their links to get more conest entries.</p>

<p>There was one slightly nefarious component to this campaign: one of the options for twitter/facebook sharing was to authorize our twitter/facebook app so that we could tweet once a day on the users behalf.  Each tweet/update was tagged with the outgoing message and the time of day.  By A/B testing messages and publication time, we were able to get these links to drive approximately half of our signups.</p>

<p>Total signups 21,065.  Total development time: 1 week. Total cost: $1500.</p>

<p>So I paid around $0.07 per email. To run the campaign for 6 weeks from mid October to the end of November. I guess I'm not sure if this was a failure. I think with my stated goal of email collection, I did quite good, however, the value of this list is questionable at best, and I can buy targeted lists of opt-in emails from confirmed real estate industry people for around a $.10/email, so its a failure compared to that.</p>

<p>My measured clickthroughs/signups/revenue as a result of this campaign weren't that great. However, November was also our best month ever in terms of both traffic and revenue.  As I write this, I feel like I should give this another look.</p>

<h3>Guerilla flyers and stickers</h3>

<p>I printed out flyers, then personally went out and put them on doors. The "riskiest" thing I did was print out stickers for Rocket Lease that were designed to fit in the corner of the Redeye (a chicago pop culture newsletter that people read on trains and buses on the way to work), then go around to the newspaper boxes and put one on each newspaper.  It was intended to look as if it was actually sponsored by Redeye, but I was waking up at 4am to go from paper bin to paper bin putting stickers on newspaper covers.</p>

<p>Approximately 1% "clickthrough rate" on the URL from the stickers on the Redeyes.</p>

<p>Lots of waking up at 4am, $70 spent on stickers, and basically no results. Huge waste of time.</p>

<h3>Purchased emails</h3>

<p>I bought an email list from one vendor. Sent about 100k emails, and got a huge unsubscribe rate.  In retrospect, the emails probably weren't legitimately acquired, and I got more annoyed hate mail than I'd like to read.  I still think email marketing is valuable, I will probably do it in 2013, but this time I'll be smarter about it and get higher quality lists.</p>

<h2>A few things I thought about but didn't execute</h2>

<h3>Chalk Art</h3>

<p>Draw rocketlease logos and information on sidewalks around Chicago, maybe or maybe not near leasing agencies...</p>

<h3>Homeless people</h3>

<p>Can I pay the guys that stand next to the freeway 20 bucks to hold a poster for me? What do these guys generally collect in a day? I wonder if they'd be game to hold up a big poster for me instead for the same amount of money?</p>

<h2>What's Next?</h2>

<p>I have a few for Rocket Lease in 2013. My initial hope had been that using online tactics would work.  I personally have a preference for the sorts of things that CODE can do to spread Rocket Lease because code is the sort of thing that can scale very quickly.  I haven't had the best results with that so now I'm currently experimenting with a more traditional sales approach.</p>

<h3>Cold Calling</h3>

<p>Cold calling leads.  I'm not sure how this will turn out, but the lead list is bigger than I can handle.  People in real estate are professional networkers and they all post their phone numbers in public forums and websites.</p>

<h3>Door to Door</h3>

<p>In person demos at leasing agencies and property management companies.  I think this will be fruitful, because Rocket Lease is genuinely useful, easier to use, and better than most of the entrenched competition.  The struggle will be identifying qualified candidates and scoring the appointments.  Maybe someone really charismatic can just show up and charm their way into demos?</p>

<h3>College evangelists</h3>

<p>College kids just <em>get</em> Rocket Lease. They're also tech savvy and great for doing demos.  Another thought here is that if they're connected to the school newspaper somehow, Rocket Lease might be able to score some .edu backlinks.</p>

<h3>Email marketing, round 2</h3>

<p>Email lists are cheaper to buy than I had originally thought.  Even if response rates are low, the numbers are so big that this could work out.</p>

<h3>Auxiliary real estate services</h3>

<p>Leasing agencies want a bunch of things, and online rental applications isn't particularly high on the list. I wonder if offering things like lead generation, posting things on craigslist on their behalf, helping them fix their websites -- at cost, or at only a small premium, would help me get in the door to have a trusted relationship where they might start using Rocket Lease.</p>

<p>People in real estate often overpay for development/web design, so there might be a way to add value here. This seems really time consuming, so it'll probably be a last resort.</p>

<h2>Wish me luck</h2>

<p>Hopefully 2013 will be the year I finally make it in startupland.  Rocket Lease has been a phenomenal learning experience so far, and I think it has the makings of a great business.  But until it gets real traction, I'm just another struggling entrepreneur.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reddit 'Advertising']]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/reddit-advertising/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T13:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/reddit-advertising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since I read about the success of Duck Duck Go's Reddit advertising campaign, I wanted to experiment a bit with advertising on Reddit.</p>

<p>I've tried a few approaches on <a href="/blog/currently-paying-150-per-conversion/" title="Paying 150 Per Conversion For Rocket Lease">Google Adwords</a> and <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-linked-in-ads/" title="Linked In Advertising Starter Guide">Linked</a> <a href="/blog/linked-in-ads-results-3-days/">In</a> without a lot of success (though I'll probably try again soon, as I think I've learned a lot since early trials).</p>

<p>With Google, I tried the traditional keyword approach, targeting keywords that are indicative of interest in Rocket Lease's services (online rental applications).  With Linked In, the goal was to target decision makers at real estate companies who might not be actively looking for a solution but seemed like probable Rocket Lease users.</p>

<h2>Approach</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com/reddit/"><img src="/images/reddit_ad.png" alt="Rocket Lease Reddit advertising" /></a></p>

<p>With Reddit, I tried an entirely different approach.  Instead of looking for users, I wanted to appeal to Redditors to help me spread the word.  I assumed that most redditors aren't landlords but almost all redditors know someone is a landlord or rents from a landlord.</p>

<p>This particular appeal was a personal request for readers to share the word.  Redditors on the internet.  They probably largely prefer doing this online.  I hoped that Redditors might be willing to spread the word. I wasn't asking for signups or money or even a lot of time -- just to share the word for a process that I think they might prefer for the next time they or someone they know rents an apartment.</p>

<p>User time is really valuable as well, so I wanted to make it as easy as possible for users to share. The <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com/reddit/">reddit landing page</a> was modeled after <a href="http://500px.com/terms">500px's excellent terms of service page</a> that has the cliff notes version alongside the actual text for easy reading.  Additionally, I tried to make it easy for users to invite landlords with a built-in form and one click twitter and facebook sharing.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com/reddit/"><img src="/images/redditeasyshare.png" alt="Easy Social Media Sharing" /></a></p>

<p>I advertised in the Real Estate subreddit -- I was the only advertiser in this category, so that means that my was displayed at the top of the page for any user browsing the subreddit directly and I also showed up on the main feed for any logged in users who subscribe to that subreddit.</p>

<p>I also spent the minimum amount advertising to the main page, which gives me exposure proportionate to the amount of money I spent ($20/day, the minimum) compared to other advertisers who were advertising on the same day.  This pool is MUCH bigger, but also generally has people who probably care less about Rocket Lease.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<p>Mostly underwhelming.</p>

<p>Over 3 days:</p>

<ul>
<li>Total cost: $150</li>
<li>503,248 impressions</li>
<li>398 clicks</li>
<li>0.079% CTR</li>
<li>6 landlord invitations</li>
<li>1.25 pages per visit (whee, 20 % of visitors probably hit the landing page, site average is 4.5 pages/visit)</li>
<li>89% bounce rate (substantially higher than my normal, but expected for redditors, site average is 45%)</li>
<li>average visit duration 37 seconds (eh not surprised, but I was hopeful for more, site average is 4:30 seconds/visit)</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="/images/reddit_results_full.png"><img src="/images/reddit_results_graph.png" alt="Results" /></a></p>

<p>5 of the landlord invitations occured on the first day, and 1 on the second day. 'Twas cool that you can see Reddit traffic patterns in the impressions.</p>

<p>See the <a href="/images/reddit_results_full.png">full hourly breakdown of the campaign</a></p>

<h2>What I Should Have Done Differently</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Test different headlines</strong>  In general, I need to start split testing more things on Rocket Lease.</li>
<li><strong>Run the campaign for longer</strong> I'm conflicted on this.  On the one hand, the 3 day traffic pattern was declining and I got all my results in the first 24 hours. CTR appeared to be generally decreasing as well over time, so that makes me think users just decided they didn't care and everyone who was going to do anything did it in the first 24 hours. However, I suspect there's some value in remaining as a persistent feature on the page to really sink into readers' subconscious.  By now, its doubtful that any redditor even remembers that campaign occured at all.  For 1000 bucks, I can stay at the top of the reddit real estate section for an entire month and change the headlines over time.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="/images/reddit_results_full.png">See the complete Reddit campaign results</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embeddable applications]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/embeddable-applications/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/embeddable-applications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>    &lt;style&gt;
        iframe { width: 100%; height: 100%; }
        div { width: 600px; height: 400px; margin: auto; }
    &lt;/style&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Hello!&lt;/h1&gt;
    Now we can embed rocketlease applications in other pages!
    &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;script src="http://code.jquery.com/jquery-1.8.0.min.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div id="rocketlease"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"&gt;Powered by RocketLease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src="http://integration.rocketlease.com/app/2-2/embedded.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
