<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: strategy | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/strategy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T11:41:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change in Linked In Ad Strategy: Free Banner Advertising?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/change-in-linked-in-ad-strategy-free-banner-advertising/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/change-in-linked-in-ad-strategy-free-banner-advertising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote about my experience <a href="http://ezliu.com/getting-started-with-linked-in-ads/">setting up Linked In Ads</a> and described why I chose the campaign set up that I did a few days ago.</p>

<p>1897 impressions and zero clicks later, I've decided to pull the plug on running the campaign that way.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.27.28-PM.png"><img title="Rocket Lease" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.27.28-PM.png" alt="" width="200" height="53" /></a></p>

<p>I mentioned that Linked In doesn't really tell you what you get for bidding more or less than the "recommended amount".  Since Linked In doesn't tell me what impact I'll get for increasing my bid, I decided I'll test it myself. For giggles, I've doubled my bid from $2.00 to $4.00/1000 impressions; this is significantly HIGHER than the recommended $2.13-$2.34 range.  Its not clear, but I think you pay whatever you bid, unlike Google Adwords auctioning system.  Will post further results.</p>

<p>I'm not surprised that Linked In isn't generating clicks.  People go to Google with specific queries and the default user behavior is "click a link". Facebook ads are even probably better because people go to Facebook when they're bored and looking for a diversion at work. Linked In, however, as far as I can tell, though described as a "social network" is a very targeted tool that people use for professional communication and is users generally only open it with a specific purpose in mind. People don't just go hang out on LI to pass time, and they aren't looking for things to click on.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/linkedinfail.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-280" title="linkedinfail" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/linkedinfail.png" alt="" width="982" height="173" /></a></p>

<p>It might be the case that only certain types of products should be advertising on Linked In (tools for recruiters, trying to reach people directly by posting your resume in an ad, job finding services, etc.).  I'll be curious to see what increased CPM bids or CPC campaigns end up doing.</p>

<p>My hope at this point is I migrate to CPC and continue to get zero clicks.  If I'm right that Linked In users just don't click because that's not why they go to the site, I'll treat this as a free awareness generation campaign.  I'll open up my target audience to get mass exposure and just use it as a way to have Rocket Lease banner ads displayed as people do whatever they do on Linked In.  It might not directly convert, but hopefully it'll start sinking into everyone's brains and the next time someone is talking about renting an apartment, maybe it will come up.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linked In Ads Results (3 days)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/linked-in-ads-results-3-days/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/linked-in-ads-results-3-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote last week about my experience <a href="http://ezliu.com/getting-started-with-linked-in-ads/">getting started with Linked In ads</a>.</p>

<p>So far, the Linked In ad experiment so far has been... underwhelming.  In fairness, it has only been 3 days, 2 of which were the weekend, but so far, Linked In advertising doesn't look like an effective strategy for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a>.</p>

<h2>Too Slow</h2>


<p>My favorite thing about Linked In ads is that you can filter down to a highly targeted audience to advertise to.  Unfortunately, as a result, I didn't get very many impressions.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/linkedin.png"><img title="linkedin" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/linkedin.png" alt="" width="969" height="173" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 3 days I got just over 1000 impressions. As expected, the CTR is lower than the Google Adwords CTR of 1.9%.  Since they are different mediums with different use cases, I didn't have a basis for estimating what the CTR would be, but I Was <em>hoping</em> it'd be &gt; 0.0%.</p>

<p>At that rate, it's hard to justify spending time on managing the Linked In ad campaign.  I'll most likely switch over to pay per click soon to see how many impressions it takes me to get a click and see if that works better than CPM.  If I don't get clicks, I may consider expanding my target audience to see if I can start collecting free impressions -- even if I don't get clicks, I'd consider it a win to be able to get impressions for free or cheap, because it might have an impact on my ability to make a conversion for that user if they ever do stop by my site through some other channel.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h2>How To Take Advantage of Linked In's Suboptimal Pricing Scheme</h2>


<p>I could speed up the impressions by opening up by target audience, but I'd have to open the audience up to less interested groups, raising my price. Linked In makes the minimum bid for clicks or impressions the same, regardless of the target audience you select.  This is a bit counterintuitive -- seems like it should be more expensive for highly targeted audiences.</p>

<p>The play to get the most value is to run campaigns for very small groups, so you can optimize for every tiny subset of the population.  It's time consuming, but will almost certainly result in the best Cost per Conversion.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h1>Needs Work</h1>


<p>The Linked In ad platform generally needs work.  The single most annoying element to me is the lack of explanation of how toggling the various inputs will impact my final campaign.</p>

<p>Less annoying, but the sort of thing that worries me and makes me think that Linked In isn't paying any attention to their Ads group -- This morning I got an email that stated supposed stats about my 2 campaigns (most importantly, that I had a non-zero amount of clicks). However, if you compare it to the screenshot above from inside my Linked In Ads dashboard,  I haven't registered any clicks.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/email.png"><img title="email" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/email.png" alt="" width="574" height="310" /></a></p>

<p>2 mistakes in the email:</p>

<ol>
    <li>The actual campaigns have *zero* clicks, so the 0.046% CTR is wrong.</li>
    <li>The 2 campaign summaries in the email display the *same* (incorrect) CTR.</li>
</ol>


<div>Linked In needs to do a better job telling people what they'll get for raising their bid as well. Tell me what I stand to gain by bidding more!</div>


<p>I still have $53 of advertising, but I doubt these ads are going to pan out for Rocket Lease.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Linked In Ads]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/getting-started-with-linked-in-ads/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/getting-started-with-linked-in-ads</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm experimenting with Linked In Ads.  This is a log of what I did, my thought processes as I made decisions, and what I found interesting during the process of setting up my first Linked In ad campaign.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-265" title="Rocket Lease" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.27.28-PM.png" alt="" width="200" height="53" /></a></p>

<h2><strong>TLDR:</strong></h2>


<ol>
    <li><strong>A lot of people are on Linked In</strong> (66 million accounts registered in the United States).</li>
    <li>Linked In is really cool because it lets you really slice up their user base for <strong>very selective demographic targeting</strong>.</li>
    <li><strong>Annoyingly, the minimum bid is $2.00/click</strong> or $2.00/1000 impressions. This strikes me as stupid and an indication that they don't have enough people running linked in ads to boost ad prices in organic auctions.  This makes me doubt the efficiency of the ads. Some people run businesses that won't convert at clicks of $2.00. Let the free market decide.</li>
    <li><strong>The UX could use improvement</strong> -- Many sections need more explanation and there aren't a lot of good/believable resources online. For example, LI tells me a recommended ad bid price, but doesn't tell me what the impact of bidding lower is. I'm not against paying more, but if I was the sort of person who would pay 10% more than the minimum without knowing why because some arbitrary text told me I should, I'd probably lose my shirt really fast in the startup game.</li>
    <li>I chose to advertise to<strong> real estat</strong>e people, and I<strong> opted to buy impressions rather than clicks</strong> (I had never considered that before setting up this campaign).</li>
</ol>


<h2>Cool Data + How To Narrow Down Your Target Audience</h2>


<p>Linked In has a cool interface where you can slice the linked in user set and it tells you how many people are in the resulting set. I thought the numbers were cool, so I'm sharing the funnel that I sliced for my first campaign.</p>

<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="All US" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/17210540389-orig.png" alt="" width="656" height="429" /></p>


<p>Filtering the Linked In user set by location: United States gives us <strong>66,628,075</strong>. That's <strong>1 account for every 3 Americans</strong> <strong>between the ages of 20 and 65</strong>. Considering that Linked In is a professional networking site, that seems like an appropriate age range, and more significantly, not all Americans in that set are (a) professional workers that would be on Linked In (service industry workers are largely not on Linked In, for example), and (b) interested in networking online.</p>

<p>If we were to pretend those numbers were real, independent, active accounts, Linked In might have close to 100% of its target user base.  Amusing. I don't know how Linked In stock is priced, but if its at market saturation, I don't imagine I want to price it like a growth stock.</p>

<h2>Filter by Industry</h2>


<p>No matter, I'm on Linked In for a very specific reason. To spread the word about Rocket Lease. Since <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease provides online rental applications and credit checks</a>, our natural users are<strong> landlords, property managers, and leasing agents</strong>.  Narrowing our area of interest to the real estate industry shrinks our target audience to <strong>1,579,593 </strong>Linked In users.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.22.33-PM.png"><img title="Linked In - Real Estate" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.22.33-PM.png" alt="" width="390" height="302" /></a></p>

<p>Another cool feature is that I can filter by company size.  A few ideas here, but the data first:</p>

<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Company Size</th>
<th>Target Audience</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 10</td>
<td>5,366</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11 - 50</td>
<td>23,480</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>51 - 200</td>
<td>70,942</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>201 - 500</td>
<td>62,195</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>501 - 1000</td>
<td>47,123</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1001 - 5000</td>
<td>130,203</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5001 - 10,000</td>
<td>31,797</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10,000+</td>
<td>102,051</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<blockquote>NOTE: This is a complete tangent, but I found it interesting so I want to post it. If you just want to read about how I set up my Linked In ads, skip this yellow box.

<strong>Weirdly, the number of people in the set is in flux</strong>. If you select a group like company size:1001-5000, you might get a estimated target audience of 130,203. Then select another group (company size:501-1000). then go back  to company size:1001-5000 -- the original number can change dramatically. When I tried it several times, the difference was as large as ~2000. Why does that change?

Also, <strong>clicking all the options for company size gave me 461,440 users compared to the 1.58 million</strong> users in the real estate industry, so there's apparently an <strong>uncategorized 1.12 million people</strong> who are in real estate companies of unspecified size.  Similarly, selecting people in all age groups is a substantially smaller set than selecting all people.

I guess one takeaway is that <strong>if you don't want to see ads on Linked In, don't specify gender, age, or company size</strong>.  Anyone you've actually met or corresponded with should be searching for you by name or email, so it shouldn't matter for networking. Recruiters shouldn't be looking for you on these criteria anyways so it won't negatively affect your Linked In experience, but it'll be way more expensive for people to advertise to you.

Another interesting thing is that the target audience and company size tell you the <strong><em>number</em> of companies in each size range</strong>.
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Company Size</th>
<th>Target Audience</th>
<th># of Companies</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&lt; 10</td>
<td>5,366</td>
<td>536 - 5,366</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11 - 50</td>
<td>23,480</td>
<td>460 - 2,300</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>51 - 200</td>
<td>70,942</td>
<td>350 - 1,400</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>201 - 500</td>
<td>62,195</td>
<td>125 - 310</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>501 - 1000</td>
<td>47,123</td>
<td>47 - 94</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1001 - 5000</td>
<td>130,203</td>
<td>26 - 130</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5001 - 10,000</td>
<td>31,797</td>
<td>3 - 6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10,000+</td>
<td>102,051</td>
<td>1 - 10</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
The target audience size from the 501-1000 &gt; 1001-5000 &gt; 5001-10,000 progression looked odd to me ( big jump from 47k -&gt; 130k, then a huge dip from 130k -&gt; 31.7k).

Correspondingly, the implied number of companies of size 5001-10,000 falls off a cliff from 26-130 companies to 3-6. "Real estate companies" is a pretty broad range of company types (construction, leasing agencies, buying raw land, REITS, etc.) so it'd be impossible to make many generalizations about real estate companies based on this data, but you might say that there's a serious hurdle for real estate companies in general to clear the 5000 employee mark.

Generally I don't think this is surprising -- for ANY company to grow that big probably requires substantial infrastructure investment and process to be able to operate as a cohesive unit.  Maybe real estate companies of that size don't operate efficiently or it's not economically justifiable or worth the effort to expand a real estate empire to be &gt; 5000 people.</blockquote>


<h2>Filter By Company Size</h2>


<p>I filtered the target audience down to <strong>companies smaller than 50</strong>.</p>

<p>Rocket Lease is a turn key solution for landlords and leasing agents to distribute rental applications on the internet. However, <strong>big leasing agencies and property managers usually process enough applications that they have a system in place</strong>, even if inefficient. Additionally, these firms are more change averse because the risks of disrupting the regularity of their system are larger.</p>

<p><strong>Small to medium size agencies and individual, non-professional landlords tend to not have systems</strong>, or be more open to third-party process optimization since they don't have the resources to implement something like automated tenant screening and online rental applications with their non-existent in-house IT departments.</p>

<p>My strategy for Rocket Lease is to initially target companies and individuals who have the ability to see a solution they like and make a snap decision to try it out. Big companies have too much bureaucracy and red tape to hope for that, so I opted to exclude them from my initial Linked In advertising efforts. This filters the estimated target audience size down to <strong>28,791</strong>.</p>

<h2>Filter by Job Function</h2>


<p>The last filter I applied was <strong>Job Function</strong>. I want to target the decision makers in companies. Obviously I want everyone to know about Rocket Lease, but it makes the most sense to target people who can actually act on a decision to implement Rocket Lease or has the direct power to pitch to the ultimate decision maker. <strong>7,597.</strong></p>

<h2>Skipping Age Filter</h2>


<p>I considered segmenting my market to people &lt;55 years of age because I think that set is, on the average, more likely to adopt tech solutions to existing problems.  However, I opted against it because I figure if someone 55+ is on linked in, they have self selected themselves as being open to technology solutions despite my global assumptions about people in that age bracket.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.24.33-PM.png"><img title="Linked In Final Filter" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.24.33-PM.png" alt="" width="394" height="447" /></a></p>

<p>United States &gt; Real Estate professionals &gt; companies smaller than 50 people &gt; people who are decision makers (CXO, Manager, Partner, etc.). <strong>7,957 United States real estate company directors and decision makers that use the internet for networking and business.</strong> And I want to show them ads.</p>

<h2>Clicks vs Impressions</h2>


<p>It was extremely annoying to me that the minimum bid per click is $2.00.  In a previous blog post, I computed that a <a href="http://ezliu.com/currently-paying-150-per-conversion/">conservative,<strong> low bound for customer LTV $4.69</strong></a> -- with my signup rates, each<strong> signup was worth $2.25</strong> (conversion != signup in the experiment). <strong>With a minimum bid of $2.00, I need a nearly 100% signup rate</strong> on clickthroughs, which is a pipe dream.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.40.30-PM.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-270" title="Annoying minimum bid" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/Screen-Shot-2012-06-22-at-9.40.30-PM.png" alt="" width="447" height="149" /></a></p>

<p>It's also a little annoying that they have a suggested bid range above the already irksome minimum bid, but there's no indication of what it means or that it will make any difference for me. Google Ads have lots of third party tutorials describing the impact of price, but Linked In does not. And Linked In, if you can't tell me <strong><em>why</em></strong> I should pay more, I'm not going to.  (Recommendation to Linked In: Please get a UI/UX person to rethink these ad creation flows.)</p>

<p>My previous measured<strong> signup rate was 5.56%</strong>, so the <strong>max I can rationally bid is $.12</strong> or so.  So if I pay per click I'm overpaying by a boatload. In fairness, I think my actual signup rate is now much higher with landing page optimizations, but it doesn't change the fact that I need to approach 100% signup, which I'm assuming is impossible.</p>

<p>I'm running this trial with the free $50 for $5 credit purchase, so its effectively a 90% discount, and that makes the numbers JUST work out at that click rate, but I don't want it to only work once, I'm looking for sustainable strategies.</p>

<p>However, I think I might be able to do better.  My global Adwords click through rate is <strong>1.93%</strong>, so if I pay the same minimum $2.00/1000 impressions and get anywhere near my adwords click through rate, I'm looking at <strong>19 clicks for the $2.00</strong>.</p>

<p>Obviously its different because people searching on Google are PLANNING on clicking SOMETHING after a search (that's what Google is for, after all), but (a) Linked In users aren't searching and (b) clicking to another page isn't the standard user behavior -- so the click through rate might be dismally lower -- but hey I didn't think of that when I set up the campaign. I know that I can't achieve a 100% sign up rate on clicks, so buying clicks is almost certainly a failing strategy -- at least with the laser focused target audience</p>

<p>Ultimately I will test both and report on which one performed better.  However, my total estimated audience size is ~7000 people, and I don't want to spend a ton readvertising to the same people, so I almost certainly won't have statistical significance.  Will follow up post as I get more data (only if it makes me look awesome, obviously).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/logo.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-262" title="logo" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/logo.png" alt="" width="46" height="46" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracking HTTP Referer To Determine True Customer Lifetime Value]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/tracking-http-referer-to-determine-true-customer-lifetime-value/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/tracking-http-referer-to-determine-true-customer-lifetime-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to be able to know what site referred users to my site.</p>

<p>More specifically, I want to be able to look back in a month, and say "users from Linked In did X over their next 10 visits."</p>

<h2>Doesn't Google Analytics do that?</h2>


<p>Not really. Google Analytics, as far as I know, will tell me where a user came from for a visit, but won't let me tie all the future behavior of the site user to their original referer.</p>

<h2>Why Is That Important?</h2>


<p><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> has different types of users. Small landlords, big landlords, property managers, leasing agents. While they interact with the site in similar ways, the strategy for connecting with each class of users differs and (I suspect) the total lifetime value of each customer class will vary.</p>

<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.rocketlease.com"><img src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/rl2-300x156.png" alt="" width="300" height="156" /></a></p>


<p>For example, I intend to advertise on various landlord and property manager forums. Professional property managers tend to manage more properties than a landlord owns, so they likely have higher lifetime value (LTV) and I might be willing to pay more per property manager conversion.</p>

<p>I need to know how much time/effort/money to allocate to advertising on Property Manager Forum X vs reddit/r/smalllandlords.</p>

<p>If there's a real difference in LTV based on user class, measuring global user LTV is a surefire way to inefficiently allocate advertising dollars.</p>

<h2>Just a Little Bit Of Middleware</h2>


<p>I had (still have) a nagging feeling that I was solving a solved problem, but I couldn't find someone else who had done it, so here's what I did.</p>

<pre class="code"><code>
# 2 space indent because my blog is skinny
class OriginalRefererMiddleware(object):
  def process_request(self, request):
    referer = request.META.get("HTTP_REFERER")
    host = request.META.get("HTTP_HOST")
    path_info = request.META.get("PATH_INFO")

    if not "ORIGINAL_HTTP_REFERER" in request.session.keys():
      request.session['ORIGINAL_HTTP_REFERER'] = referer

    if not 'ENTRY_PAGE' in request.session.keys():
      request.session['ENTRY_PAGE'] = host + path_info
</code></pre>




<br />


<p>HTTP requests come with a HTTP_REFERER header that me what page the user clicked through from. So if a user ends on my landing page from linked in, if I extract the HTTP_HEADER, it'll say linked in. But then if they go to my FAQ, now the referer is "<strong>rocketlease.com</strong>", then if they sign up from there, the referer will be "<strong>rocketlease.com/faq</strong>".</p>

<p>Instead, the first time (and only the first time) a user lands on any page served by me, I save the value of the referer. Then when the user finally registers, I just dump the original_referer to my database so at any future time I can determine how any user originally arrived at my site.</p>

<p>I'm planning on experimenting with LinkedIn, Facebook, and Bing ads in the next 2 weeks, so hopefully this will help me determine where I should be allocating ad spend. Linked In and Facebook in particular make it possible for me to target certain classes of users. Rocket Lease basically never makes an actual sale on the initial interaction with a user, so using the ad services' built in analytics isn't sufficient to determine value of a customer class.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popular Craigslist Spam Tactics for Profit (and for Evil)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/craigslist/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/craigslist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've always enjoyed <a href="http://davegooden.com/2011/05/how-airbnb-became-a-billion-dollar-company/">Dave Gooden's fantastic writeup</a> about how AirBnB benefitted from email marketing tactics on Craigslist and wondered how prevalent the use of such tactics was. (It'd also be interesting to know if that happens a lot <em>more</em> after his blog post was published)</p>

<p>Mike L and I were chatting about it and I decided to chronicle a few craigslist scam/spam/marketing techniques we've seen (with <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/">links to the actual email threads in each section</a>)</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-205" title="kimmie" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/kimmie.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="320" /></p>

<h2><strong>"Unthreatening Potential Female Roommate Just Wants Confirmation That You Can Pay Bills"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Please Run A Credit Check"
<strong>Actual Example:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental1.html">credit</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Free Credit Report.com</p>

<p>Mike was looking for a new apartment and responded to an ad in the roommates section. A cute girl responded.</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Female responder, girls get better response rates, especially cute ones.</li>
    <li>Wants to make sure you're not a scammer</li>
    <li>Well written email, very conversational, disarming.</li>
    <li>This email is too well crafted, it is unlikely to have been sent through a text spinner -- which means that its probably more targeted, and the risk of being sent to spam folders is much higher.</li>
    <li>Really LONG email. Seriously, whoever did this should rethink it, because nobody reads emails that long. Or is it part of the play? It clearly COULDN'T be a spam message!</li>
    <li>Girl is believably cute, not devastatingly hot.</li>
    <li>Eating ice cream in the picture. Come on, how non-threatening is that?</li>
    <li>Asks you to send her credit check info, but as a helpful citizen tells you to make sure to withold your SSN. Again, she's not a scammer! Conveniently recommends FreeCreditReport.com</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Their action:</strong> There are two common plays here.</p>

<ul>
    <li>post ads on craigslist seeking roommates. Whenever someone responds, send them this email encouraging them to try out freecreditreport.com</li>
    <li>Respond to ads where people are seeking roomates. If they respond back, game on.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Benefit of this:</strong> HUGE reduction of total email send volume, everyone who responds to you is already qualifying themselves as an interested candidate and giving you a real email address.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/banana.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-78" title="banana" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/banana-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>

<h2><strong>"Helpful Internet Citizen Trying To Help You Avoid Contractor Woes"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>Note:</strong> This spam was found to be a third party abusing an affiliate program. The actual company reached out and informed me that they don't condone that behavior and have banned the affiliate marketer. Their logo above was replaced by a photo of a banana. Why? Because I happened to have one in my Wordpress Media Library.</p>

<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Let Me Recommend A Site I've Used Successfully"
<strong>Actual Example:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/odesk.html">contractor site</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> An contracting site</p>

<p>I was looking for someone to reskin a wordpress blog for me. A very helpful girl named Ava who recently had a bad craigslist experience wanted to let me know that a specific contracting site gave her better results.</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Short and sweet</li>
    <li>Also from a girl</li>
    <li>Voice a common concern, just trying to save you the trouble she went through.</li>
    <li>Smoking gun: the link doesn't go to the site itself. it goes to a click tracking site. Regular humans don't do that.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Their action:</strong> scrape craigslist computer gigs section, respond to everyone and recommend a specific site as a superior alternative.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/scam2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-209" title="scam" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/scam2.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="190" /></a></p>




<h2></h2>


<h2><strong>"Christian In West Africa Wants To Rent Lovely Home To You"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA:</strong> "Give Me All Your Info"
<strong>Actual Examples:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2a.html">[a]</a> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2b.html">[b]</a> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/rental2c.html">[c]</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Some scammer/identity thief (This is the only one that I find particularly evil.)</p>

<p>I responded to several ads in the craigslist "apartments for rent" section. One particular flavor of response stood out.</p>

<p>There were a lot of autoresponses from places with great, submarket rents, and they all ask you to fill out a rental application<strong> including a lot of personal information.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Responses were all from emails sent to listings where the original poster had used a public email address (as opposed to an anonymized craigslist address)</li>
    <li>Typical pattern is that someone lived in a gorgeous home, but had to go abroad.</li>
    <li>Abroad is typically West Africa, I have no idea why.</li>
    <li>Most of the respondents represent themselves as Christian (a reverand, a family doing missions in west africa, etc.)</li>
    <li>Tend to act as if they are aware you have the upper hand, but need to trust you (suddenly had to move away, need the money, willing to rent to you at a lower price if you're a good tenant, just prove it by emailing me your personal information). I think this is a play to disarm your suspicion.</li>
    <li>They generally display some sort of concern that they are going to be scammed themselves or a vulnerability that makes them want to qualify you as a tenant. For example, it is their personal family home, they have their furniture there and want to make sure it's in good hands in their absence.</li>
    <li>Prey on typical US perceptions of trustworthiness: Christians, ministers, reverends, families with young children</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Lessons learned:</strong>
Mostly spammers post "real" addresses. Real "real" people are afraid of posting their address in the open.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ezliu.com//images/b-e1339030520918-250x300.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-210" title="b" src="http://www.ezliu.com//images/b-e1339030520918-250x300.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /></a></p>

<h2><strong>"Horny Young Co-Ed Wants To Chat"</strong></h2>


<p><strong>AKA</strong> "Men Like Nude Women"
<strong>Actual Examples:</strong> <a href="http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/adult.html">http://ezl.github.com/craigslistspam/adult.html</a>
<strong>Beneficiary:</strong> Actually, I don't quite get this one. I assume the site somehow generates revenue from desperate men who want to hook up with hot sexy co-eds for free! (just enter your credit card! we won't use it! trust us!)</p>

<p>This is pretty interesting actually.</p>

<p>Mike gave a girl a copy of the Redeye, a daily pop culture/sports newspaperlet in Chicago.
He later posted in Missed Connections about it, and received a garbage reply:</p>

<p>Not thinking about it, he responded with a short one liner and unleashed upon himself the fury that is adult website spammers.</p>

<p>Every day since, he has received at least 1 unsolicited emails from different girls just trying to get him to sign up for a site to connect with hot girls like her that want to chat. The really amusing thing is that (1) many of these "different" girls somehow have the same picture, and (2) the emails are almost all identical. As a teaser, these girls all send nude pics of themselves, and amazingly, sometimes their nude pics don't even look like the same girl (weird, I know).</p>

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ul>
    <li>Tries to act like a sexy coed who is afraid YOU are a scammer of some sort. She just wants to make sure she's not chatting with a "cam girl or a bot", which is clearly the spammers play to make you think *she* isn't a "cam girl or a bot"</li>
    <li>Clearly using an automated program to vary the text of the messages, probably as an attempt to avoid email spam filters</li>
    <li>Huge corpus of alternate urls for their site.</li>
    <li>All sent from different email addresses.</li>
    <li>Whose naked photos are these?!</li>
</ul>


<h2>"Spam" is not equal to "Scam"</h2>


<div><a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4079583">Callmeed on HN</a> made a point about distinguishing between "spam" and "scam".</div>


<div></div>


<div>The "Christian in West Africa Wants To Rent Lovely Home To You" category is the only one that I feel really bad about, because these people are screwing people over. The other ones are just companies doing some guerilla marketing. The "hot, horny women" category seems a little sleazy, and I don't actually know that they're NOT doing bad things with the data they collect (or what they collect), but on the surface it just seems like a spammy campaign to drive traffic.</div>


<h2>Common Characteristics in Many Craigslist Spam/Scam Messages</h2>


<ul>
    <li>Build rapport. Voice a common concern that you probably have to disqualify self as the threat.</li>
    <li>Act as an independent, concerned citizen. recommending a third party service.</li>
    <li>Respondents are female or generally prey on typical American stereotypes of honesty (Christian, African Foreign AID volunteer, social worker).</li>
    <li>Pose as vulnerable to empower the target</li>
    <li>Too good to be true</li>
</ul>


<p>The adult site one amuses me in particular because it is the most technically involved -- clearly using spinner code, likely for spam filter evasion; probably a script that autoregisters accounts with free services, so they might also have to be beating captchas; they are sending the largest total volume of email too, so they probably have to deal sending through lots of proxies to avoid getting blacklisted by the free mail services; tons of domains involved; and at the end of it, it seems like the least likely to get conversions.</p>

<p>Generally I think this stuff is pretty cool. With the exception of the spammers who pretend to give you rental applications, probably as a ploy to steal your identity, I consider these mostly just interesting "grey hat" marketing tactics.</p>

<p>Airbnb wasn't the only one. I imagine that there are probably even 3rd party "marketing companies" that do this for your startup.  I'd be interested in hearing more about it from the inside -- if you're reading this and you know someone who might be willing to talk to me, even anonymously, please connect me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
