<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sales | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/sales/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-21T13:25:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Hire Salespeople For A Startup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/how-to-hire-salespeople-for-a-startup/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T10:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/how-to-hire-salespeople-for-a-startup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Before You Post Your Ad</h2>

<h3>Don't be afraid to spend 25 bucks on a job post</h3>

<p>Say what you will about Craigslist, it's still where everyone goes to find jobs.
It costs $25 to post in the jobs section. You can post in the gigs section for free. If you're not ready to invest $25 to get better candidates,
you're not ready to invest in a salesperson.</p>

<h3>Don't make it too easy</h3>

<p>Don't give them all the information they need. Make them hunt through your website for
your contact info. Or linked in. Make your information available, but not obvious. This will weed out people who are just mass mailing
resumes.</p>

<h3>Set up phone interviews</h3>

<p>Set up a phone interview for some time in the future. Give them 2 options, and ask them to pick one that works for them. Have them call you
at the stated time. You are looking for: (a) a confirmation email "yes, i'll call you at time X", and (b) that they actually call on time.</p>

<p>These are important because they weed out (a) people who can't communicate clearly about future events/expectations and (b) candidates who
are unreliable or can't manage their calendar [managing future calls is important for followups to prospects]</p>

<h3>The interview starts when they contact you first</h3>

<p>Typos in emails, an inability to communicate effectively via email, unreliable, missed phone calls, are all reasons to end the process.
There are lots of fantastic salespeople out there, don't settle for those with obvious deficits.</p>

<h2>The Phone Interview</h2>

<h3>If you aren't convinced by the interview, prospects won't be convinced by their sales pitch</h3>

<p>The phone interview is a sales call where the salesperson is selling himself to you.
Is he smooth on the phone, does he guide the conversation, does he ask good questions, is
he personable, do you like him?</p>

<ul>
<li>Do they ramble? If they do, let them go. See how long it goes. Sales isn't about the salesperson, it's about the prospect. Talking forever about themselves is a negative indicator.</li>
<li>If the conversation stops, do NOT fill the space for them -- see what they do with the awkward silence.</li>
<li>Do they overuse filler words like "um" and "like"? You want someone that sounds smooth, assertive, and confident. If they don't sound professional and convincing in an interview, they won't when they sell your product.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Great candidates will ask you questions about the role, what you need, and tell you if it's a good fit.</h3>

<p>Awesomeness doesn't happen in a vacuum. You don't want a candidate who is just awesome alone --
he/she has to be awesome with your product.</p>

<p>Do they tell stories about themselves like they're trying too hard to sell themselves? Great sales
is about finding <strong>FIT</strong>, not talking about how AWESOME your product is.  They should be asking about
your NEEDS and seeing how they can fill them.  They should be asking a lot of questions, not regaling
you with stories of how much revenue they closed in an unrelated industry.</p>

<p><strong>There's no perfect salesperson and there's no perfect product.</strong></p>

<p>The salesperson's job is to find out the prospect's needs/pain points, then show how your product
can solve that. If he's not looking for fit between him and you, he won't be looking for fit between
your product and your customers.</p>

<h3>What sorts of things can't you sell / What was the hardest thing you've ever had to sell?</h3>

<p>Salespeople love to say they can sell anything. That's never true. Some products
are too expensive, or don't have product-market fit, or just plain suck.  Ask what they struggled to sell or
what sorts of products they think they wouldn't be able to sell. If the answer is "nothing", it indicates
either delusion or an inability to reason.</p>

<h3>Metrics</h3>

<p>Ask them what sorts of metrics they track and how they track them.  Calls, decision makers, demos, etc.
How do they typically gauge success?</p>

<p>Also, what system do they use for tracking it (assuming you don't already
have this stuff in place).  As a founder, your job isn't to train people to sell. You want people who
already think about this the right way. You need metrics, and good salespeople will have answers for you.</p>

<h3>Do they set a time to follow up?</h3>

<p><strong>This is important.</strong></p>

<p>Wind down the interview in typical fashion. Thank them for their time. Don't offer any future plans. Refrain from
saying "ok, if i'm interested, i'll get back to you next week" or something like that. Just thank them.</p>

<p>A salesperson's
job is to make sales. But many products require multiple touchpoints with busy people. Your salesperson needs to
be effective at getting to the next step.</p>

<p>Salespeople can waste a
lot of time chasing dead leads that aren't interested.  To be efficient, they need to be able to identify which leads
are dead and prune them. At the end of any sales call, they should be either:</p>

<ul>
<li>(a) realizing that the lead is no good, or</li>
<li>(b) scheduling a specific follow up time</li>
</ul>


<p>If they don't either (a) try to eliminate themselves from the running, or (b) nail you down to a specific future time,
won't do that with prospects.</p>

<p>Great questions:</p>

<ul>
<li>"What are you looking for in order to make a decision"</li>
<li>"What could make you decide to either hire me or eliminate me as a candidate right now?"</li>
<li>"In what timeframe do you intend to make a decision"</li>
<li>"OK, so if I don't hear from you by Friday, would it be ok for me to reach out to you on Monday to follow up?"</li>
</ul>


<p>The result of this is that they'll be forced to follow up in the future. See if they do.
If they can't get their calendar together for a job, they'll fail with prospects.</p>

<h2>Other thoughts</h2>

<h3>Typing speed</h3>

<p>This is usually a pretty good indicator of computer usage and that's important to me:</p>

<ul>
<li>I do screensharing demos for Rocket Lease. A prospect gets bored watching you slowly type in a bunch of fields on a form.</li>
<li>I communicate via email. If written text is important for you to communicate, you probably type reasonably fast as well.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Hotmail accounts</h3>

<p>This is a bad filter, and I don't recommend it for everyone, but if you're writing me from a hotmail
account, wtf? Who uses that anymore?</p>

<p>I sell a tech product, and most people who live on the internet don't use hotmail anymore.</p>

<h3>Ask your interviewee what you should be looking for</h3>

<p>You want candidates who are realistic, and can make decisions on behalf of your company. Ask the candidate
what he/she thinks you should be looking for in a hire. Basically, put him/her in the interviewer's shoes.</p>

<p>Great candidates are comfortable stepping outside of the interviewee role and giving answers that aren't
just "pick me, pick me!"</p>

<h3>Try to talk them out of the job (thanks TG)</h3>

<p><em>"This job isn't for everyone... Well, we're a startup, and so a lot of times that means it's not very structured... some
people hate that... you may be able to make more money in the short term somewhere else..."</em></p>

<p>You're not trying to scare them off, but this will help bring out some of the real issues with the job, their requirements,
and determine if it's really a fit.</p>

<p>This might seem like you're scaring away good candidates, but if you start down a path with someone where it's not a fit,
you'll be wasting your own time and resources, so you'd rather filter aggressively and be left with more high probability candidates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
