<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ideas | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/ideas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-21T13:25:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Ideas (That I Like)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/free-ideas-that-i-like/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T10:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/free-ideas-that-i-like</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some ideas I like, but am not pursuing.</p>

<p>These ideas are, of course, free for the taking, if anyone reads these and cares.  I've thought about them more than the text indicates, so if anyone wants to execute, shoot me a note and I'm happy to chat further.</p>

<h3>Put together family plans for people (cell plans, data plans)</h3>

<p>Individuals pay as much as a 50% premium for having an individual plan instead of a family plan. No cell phone carrier requires any sort of restrictions for being a "family" other than your assertion that you are a family (doesn't have to be same household, last name, or anything). You and I could be on a family plan.</p>

<p>Just a quick survey:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.att.com/shop/wireless/plans/familyplans.html">http://www.att.com/shop/wireless/plans/familyplans.html</a> vs</li>
<li><a href="http://www.att.com/shop/wireless/plans/individualplans.html">http://www.att.com/shop/wireless/plans/individualplans.html</a></li>
</ul>


<p>5 people is the max on a family plan. the unlimited plan divided 5 ways would be:</p>

<ul>
<li>(50 * 3+119) / 5 == 270/5 == 54 bucks</li>
<li>the individual unlimited plan is 70 bucks.</li>
</ul>


<p>Win.</p>

<ul>
<li>If you were to divide up the 2100 minute plan (420 minutes each),</li>
<li>(10 * 3+110)/5 ==140/5 = 28/month</li>
<li>Compare to the 450 minute individual plan for 40/mo.</li>
</ul>


<p>Win.</p>

<p>Additionally realize that with any fixed, finite amount of minutes, most people don't spend all of it. Cell phone providers make a lot of money because they're effectively dealing in "overage". If I sell you 450 minutes, you'll almost certainly use some amount OTHER than 450. If you use 400 minutes, I pocket a free 50 minutes (not always, with "rollover minutes", but whatever). If you use 500 minutes, I get to charge you for 50 minutes at some obscene overate rate. bundling packages helps people save on this front as well.</p>

<p>There's a bit more complexity than that due to data and text plans, but you get the picture.  There are also other advantages to grouping people into family plans (for example, no contract breakage fees -- you could get on a family plan for 3 months, then bail)</p>

<p>this "business idea" is just a website that pairs people together to get into family plans with people they don't know.  you could be VERY involved (actually broker the transactions, take money, and have a ton of plans yourself), or decentralize it and just connect people who are looking to save money.  Either way, you create a lot of value, so you can charge the end customer a bit.</p>

<h3>Gym waiver forms</h3>

<p>I do crossfit, which if you don't know what that is, its just another gym.  Crossfit gyms ("boxes"), dance studios, rock climbing places, karate dojos, etc all make new members sign a waiver of some sort. It's usually a crappy piece of paper that has been photocopied many times over, is hard to read, low fidelity, stored in a manila envelope in the office, and then after its signed, the gym owner files it away in a cabinet. No big deal. But they suck.</p>

<p>Create a simple version of the online signing interface at http://signnow.com, specialize in just dropping a signature and date field into an HTML document for gym owners and charge them $.50 a signature.  In return, they get electronic copies of their documents, you host/store all the documents for them ("in the cloud!" people love hearing that...). their docs are searchable and they can find whatever they want, whehever. They only pay for usage and its cheap. It automticaly emails copies to the owner and the new member. new members can just go to: gymwaiverform.com/mygymname on their phone to get the waiver, fill out a few html fields, drag their finger on the iphone as a signature, and boom.</p>

<p>the value proposition is cheap, searchable documents. always having them on hand. not having paper in your gym. email copies to you and the end consumers.</p>

<h3>Build your own granola bars</h3>

<p>Like this site: http://www.youbars.com/buildabar/ -- create a sexy UI for building your own bar.  This site should be a ONE PAGE app. use backbone or something with a list of ingredients in a checkbox, then do quick animations to make it look like items are being poured into a mold.  Do batches of 12, ship them cheap.  These are easy to make and cost like 20 cents a granola bar at most.  It's easy to hire people to do this kind of work, shipping is easy, spoilage is minimal. Target audience == office drones who are eating unhealthy crap during the day. Get them all on a weekly subscription plan.</p>

<p>The game here is to connect with office managers on linked in. ask them if you can send them a free sample. tell them its better tasting and better for their employees health than the cheetos they're already buying.  close weekly subscription plans for offices.</p>

<h3>Connect dog walkers with dog owners</h3>

<p>Tons of dog owners in cities like chicago, NYC, SF, LA pay people to walk their dogs while they're at work. Create the 2 sided market for this service exclusively. build in reviews and rating systems for both sides (a la Uber).</p>

<p>This may sound ridiculous, but this market is surprisingly bigger than you'd think (I have seen a dog walking companies financials and I was flabbergasted). Charge 5 bucks to connect a pair. Or have them book and pay through the site and charge $1 per walk (dogs are getting walked every day...).  Dog owners will probably like the convenience of online payment instead of always running to bank of america to get cash for their walker.  also, if their walker is unavailable, they'll be able to find another local walker that is well-reviewed.</p>

<p>This idea sort of exists. But nobody has traction. If dog owners/walkers don't know about it, then it effectively doesn't exist for them</p>

<h3>Booze delivery</h3>

<p>If you've ever been drunk and out of vodka, would you have paid a 5 dollar premium to have it delivered to your door in 30 minutes? Someone will.</p>

<p>Booze is cheap for liquor stores. If you can help them move product, someone will offer you a commission (call it an advertising fee, selling liquor requires abiding by laws, advertising doesn;t).</p>

<p>Drunk people pay a premium for delivery.</p>

<p>so that $25 bottle at the store, could be a $10 fee for the delivery business (5 from the store, 5 from the consumer).</p>

<p>the tech is minimal. a really clean and simple UI for picking between 4-5 choices (absolut, $15; grey goose $35; jack daniels $25, patron, $30; case of budweiser $20), an html form to take in name, address, and an image of your photo id, and a embedded stripe form for processing payments.</p>

<p>at the early stage, this just fires an email to the CEO.</p>

<p>The CEO's job is to promote this website, get people buying, manage bike messengers/drivers to deliver the product.</p>

<p>After he's delivered 100 orders, then talk about automation and scaling.</p>

<h3>CSS Bounties.com</h3>

<p>I suck at CSS. Lots of people are good at it.</p>

<p>Often, in 10 minutes, someone can solve the sort of problem that could take me 6 hours to solve.</p>

<p>Put bounties on CSS problems for immediate solving. Inspired by <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/forhire/comments/17ne2z/hiring_20_to_whomever_tells_me_how_to_fix_this_css/">this reddit thread</a>.</p>

<p>Let the internet solve your CSS problems, collaborate with the folks in #css on freenode.</p>

<p>The person with the problem posts a description, URL to the site, and the desired outcome on the site and an expiration date.  They paypal the site with the bounty (minimum $5).  They can cancel the bounty at any time before a solution is posted.</p>

<p>If the expiration date hits without a solution, it is returned to the poster.</p>

<p>People can post solutions to problems, if theirs is selected, the bounty is released to that person.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idea: Hustler School]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/idea-hustler-school/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T11:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/idea-hustler-school</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Non-technical people frequently approach me to build them an MVP. "<em>Why should
I work with you?</em>", I ask. "<em>Because I'm a great hustler</em>", they respond.</p>

<p>A lot of these people claim to have access to capital, connections,
tons of domain expertise, or whatever. Basically, there are a lot of great
hustlers in the making, but they don't have a track record and can't prove
that they are good hustlers.</p>

<p>I'd like to invert the typical "incubator" process. Applicants pay money,
buy into a company, get an MVP, and hustle.</p>

<p>First time hustlers, this is where I tell you to put your money where your
mouth is. Stop saying "if only i had product, i'd be an awesome hustler"</p>

<p>For $5,000, you get half of the company (an MVP), and operate as the CEO for
3 months. We will agree upon guidelines for success/failure metrics and if
you are the hustler you claim to be, you'll win big.</p>

<p>If you fail, you'll be forced to either recognize that you're not the hustler
you thought you were or explain how/why you failed.</p>

<p>New hustlers <strong>wildly</strong> underestimate the amount of effort it takes to get
traction, how much unglamorous grunt work there is, and don't have a good
idea of how to methodically test approaches to traction.  Many new hustlers
are also often attracted to the glamour of startups but are pretty lazy when
it's not just sitting around and talking ideas.</p>

<p>The hustler's job is to take a mutually agreed upon idea (probably an MVP of my
choosing), and get traction.</p>

<p>The hustler pays $5k, gets a functioning MVP (that he/she agrees to work on),
options for 50% of the company, then hustles:</p>

<ul>
<li>write blog posts</li>
<li>seo that sucker</li>
<li>create landing pages</li>
<li>cold call</li>
<li>pass out flyers</li>
<li>do logistics for our new food delivery service</li>
<li>do dishes</li>
<li>find an office space</li>
<li>learn about a/b testing</li>
<li>raise money</li>
</ul>


<p>or any number of hustlery things.</p>

<p>The "fund" provides guidance on these things, points hustlers in the right direction,
but the responsibility is mostly on the hustler to move the needle.</p>

<p>The MVP is what you get, but obviously I'd like to protect my investment as well, so
if it's clear that further development is helpful or required, we'll do that as well.
The hustler, of course, will have to justify the development cost (You are the CEO
after all).</p>

<p>If you hit the agreed upon success metrics, then lets talk about building <em>your</em> idea.</p>

<p>The pot of gold at the end of the rainbow is that if you're really half the hustler
you claim to be:</p>

<ol>
<li>you'll end up with a substantial equity stake in a business I think is profitable</li>
<li>you'll have a track record</li>
<li>I'll probably be pretty excited about building YOUR product too</li>
</ol>


<p>Show me that you add value. It's not hard, but it's a lot of work.</p>

<p>Regarding a 5k buy in -- A lot of people will be turned off by this. That's ok.  Most
of those "hustlers" will talk about ideas for the next year and get nothing done.</p>

<p>Any hustler that can't raise $5000 isn't much of a hustler at all.</p>

<p>I'll lose some great hustlers with that filter, but I'm willing to give that up for the
better signal to noise ratio.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Equity Pool / Founder Failure Insurance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T10:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My startup is unlikely to succeed. Your startup is unlikely to succeed.</p>

<p>Does anyone want to throw a couple points of equity into a pool to hedge their bets? I like to think of this as "founder failure insurance".</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: I have no idea what the legal ramifications of this are, and the details are definitely tricky.  Critics will almost certainly say "this is impossible legally" and/or "this would never work in practice".</p>

<p>I know that <em>I</em> personally, for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> would be interested in hedging my success in a portfolio with other founders.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>I don't know how it works. I know that a naive flavor of this, in its simplest form, looks something like:</p>

<div class="note">
<p>10 founders get together, donate 3% of their respective companies to a pool in return for 10% of the returns of the portfolio.</p>

<p>Then maybe something like 7 founders fail, 1 breaks even, 1 gets acquired, and 1 makes a real run for the big bucks.  The ones that failed end up making a little back since they're part of the pool. The big winner gives up a little of the company returns, but hopefully he's not a greedy bastard and he is still happy that he paid a little insurance in case he was one of the failures.</p>
</div>


<p>Ideally if your startup succeeds, you get disproportionately large returns and you're so rich anyway you don't remember what piddling amounts like 3% of your company were.</p>

<h2>Gotchas</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Voting</strong> -- As a group, you'd want to invest in only good bets (insurance companies don't like insuring risky people either).  However, great founders and great ideas fail too, sometimes for reasons outside their control. The group probably can't just let companies in willy nilly, because bad founders would be incentivized to join the pool, contribute equity that becomes ultimately worthless, and reap the rewards of others. Some quorum would probably have to vote in new members.</li>
<li><strong>Failure</strong> -- what happens with failures? The entire point of the pool is to make something even when you fail.</li>
<li><strong>Dilution</strong> -- I imagine that founders probably just give x% of the equity when joining the fund and it just gets diluted out with future investment and such.  Can't do anything special here because we don't want the pool to penalize the companies chances of success (investors who don't like ugly cap tables or weird preferred shares)</li>
<li><strong>Variable Contribution/Buy-In</strong> -- maybe some founders only want to give up 1% and another founder wants to donate 10%. Should unequal contributions be allowed? Or just tell everybody they're in for 3% in return for an equal share of the resulting portfolio? If variable contributions are allowed, the pool quorum has to determine what amount of the prospective portfolio company they want in return</li>
<li><strong>Buying Out / Quitting</strong> -- Buying out your poriton of the pool? Is this legit? The pool doesn't want the next Heroku's founders to buy out their shares right before they know they're going to get bought.  At the same time, we don't want high performing companies to get penalized with the addition of a lot of garbage companies.</li>
<li><strong>Management Fee</strong> -- Legal isn't cheap. Give an attorney 30 basis points to keep him happy? And does the fund need a manager? Obviously as a participant, I want it to be as cheap as possible for myself, but I'd also love to not be the one in charge of managing this.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Why I want to do this</h2>

<p>I think this would be a fun idea, but I don't know if its feasible or what the details would have to look like. If you are a critic, please tell me why it sucks (and preferably, how it can be workable). If you are interested, please tell me so we can start scheming. <a href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Email me.</a></p>

<p>One cool thing about this is that it also gives participants a pool of other (hopefully high quality) founders that they are personally invested in seeing succeed. Participants might also see interesting dealflow from other early stage startups.</p>

<p>There doesn't have to be just one of these.  Any group of founder friends who is interested in equity swapping can do so, with their own private agreements.</p>

<p>This is the result of a conversation a few nights ago at 25 degrees with CG and CQ. I had previously also spoken with JF at the Brandery about this.  All have expressed some interest in exploring this, so might already have a few people in on this.</p>

<p><a style="color:#D20606; font-size:1.5em; text-decoration:underline;" href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Join in on the fun</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YourSiteCouldLookLike.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old gym has a website that renders terribly on mobile, yet everybody at the gym goes to it every day to see the workout (that may sound weird, just trust me that it's a typical crossfit gym thing).</p>

<p>Everybody goes to the site every day to see ONE thing: the workout of the day.  Then you get there and have to pinch and zoom to read it.</p>

<p>I want a mobile version. So I threw together my own stylesheet for it. It'd be great if I could show my friends.</p>

<h2><strong>Somebody Please Build This</strong></h2>


<p><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com</strong></p>

<p>"Your Site Could Look Like" is a website. Sort of like <strong>bitly, but it doesn't just redirect, it loads the target page AND adds additional stylesheet rules</strong> to it. Basically, it lets you apply any css to any website and show it off to your friends (or the customer who you are trying to woo).</p>

<h2><strong>How it works</strong></h2>


<p>On the main page there are 2 input fields and a submit button.</p>

<blockquote>
<div>1) Target Site URL:</div>
<div>2) CSS file location:</div>
<div>3) [Submit button]</div>
</blockquote>


<p>User puts in a website and an alt stylesheet for it. On clicking submit, they get back a unique url:</p>

<blockquote>
<div><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com/xT6j2</strong></div></blockquote>


<p>Set up an nginx/apache reverse proxy. Whenever someone accesses that URL, the service curls the target site (1), inserts the contents of the CSS file immediately before the closing html tag (2), then serves the page to the customer.</p>

<p>If you want to be fancy, you can count page views, do analytics on the ip addresses that access it, etc. You can also let people insert their own js file. Will someone build this please?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
