<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ideas | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/ideas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-13T11:13:46-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Failure Insurance: Follow up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T17:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-failure-insurance-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a few interested queries when I wrote first about <a href="/blog/founder-equity-pool/">Founder Failure Insurance</a> and I've thought about it a bit more since then.</p>

<p>Today I received a short and sweet email from TV:</p>

<blockquote><p>Interesting premise.  Not saying I would contribute but would love to hear more about it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Naturally, I thought it would be sensible to ramble endlessly in response. Here's what I wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>'Twas really mostly an idea at a bar amongst friends.</p>

<p>I think there's a lot of sense in it, its essentially portfolio diversification.  As a single founder you're just investing 100% in your own stock and nobody else's.  You're constrained to one industry, one vertical, and one implementation.  You are basically ALL variance.</p>

<p>Ideally, as a founder, you should feel like you're working on the best stock, so in a sense, trading any of your company for other companies might be a negative expected value play -- however, by picking partner/portfolio companies effectively you decrease your return variance. Pick your poison.</p>

<p>Realistically, even though you should think your idea is the best, you should also hopefully accept that your idea <em>might not</em> be the best, the highest EV, or the most likely to succeed.  Then a founder's insurance fund makes total sense.</p>

<p>Of course, you can't just throw equity willy nilly into a pool of losers equity.  In the ideal case for any individual founder, they are the dog of the pool.  You want to put 5% into a pool with the next Stripe, Airbnb, Heroku, and Dropbox.  Of course, they want the same.  So you'll have to find a situation where you're equally yoked.  You need to have something they want, and they need to have something you want.</p>

<p>There are a couple of obvious flavors of this:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Industry diversification:</strong> I'm in real estate. I think mobile is hot. Someone else is doing a more stable consumer play.  An enterprise person. Different profiles of returns with different difficulties, but essentially betting on other founders to rock it in their field.  Each founders is effectively investing into a hand chosen seed fund thats trying to hedge its bets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Industry saturation:</strong> Well shit, There will definitely be an open table competitor that crushes open table.  There are probably 50 companies that are trying. Three person shops that have decent idea but might not make it. One, or a few of these companies will make a run at it, maybe merge, and emerge victorious.  You all have a shot.  Equity in a pool early on ensures that (a) you guys are incentivized to share and help each other out, improving all of your odds, (b) if your company isn't the winner, you still get to participate on the rewards.  Basically, you know you picked the right sector, but how do you know if you've picked the right name? This lets you eliminate the idiosyncratic risk (in the extreme where ALL the viable startups in a space are pooled).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In practice, you'll end up finding like minded people. If you get in a group of founders thats too good for you, they won't want your equity. If you're too good for them, you won't want their equity.  Everyone wants to imagine that they're the best founder.  You'll probably just have to be different enough that your the best in at least one dimension that makes you desirable to the others.</p>

<p>I've had a few interesting conversations with founders.  The biggest hurdle to this right now is distribution.  If we were to find 10 founders that were interested, that wouldn't be enough because we'd need to subclass that group into equally good/likely/viable startups/founders.  We need 100s of founders to jump into a dating pool and select each other.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you think there's anything interesting about this idea, the best thing you can do is help me spread it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Equity Pool / Founder Failure Insurance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T10:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/founder-equity-pool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My startup is unlikely to succeed. Your startup is unlikely to succeed.</p>

<p>Does anyone want to throw a couple points of equity into a pool to hedge their bets? I like to think of this as "founder failure insurance".</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: I have no idea what the legal ramifications of this are, and the details are definitely tricky.  Critics will almost certainly say "this is impossible legally" and/or "this would never work in practice".</p>

<p>I know that <em>I</em> personally, for <a href="http://www.rocketlease.com">Rocket Lease</a> would be interested in hedging my success in a portfolio with other founders.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>I don't know how it works. I know that a naive flavor of this, in its simplest form, looks something like:</p>

<div class="note">
<p>10 founders get together, donate 3% of their respective companies to a pool in return for 10% of the returns of the portfolio.</p>

<p>Then maybe something like 7 founders fail, 1 breaks even, 1 gets acquired, and 1 makes a real run for the big bucks.  The ones that failed end up making a little back since they're part of the pool. The big winner gives up a little of the company returns, but hopefully he's not a greedy bastard and he is still happy that he paid a little insurance in case he was one of the failures.</p>
</div>


<p>Ideally if your startup succeeds, you get disproportionately large returns and you're so rich anyway you don't remember what piddling amounts like 3% of your company were.</p>

<h2>Gotchas</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Voting</strong> -- As a group, you'd want to invest in only good bets (insurance companies don't like insuring risky people either).  However, great founders and great ideas fail too, sometimes for reasons outside their control. The group probably can't just let companies in willy nilly, because bad founders would be incentivized to join the pool, contribute equity that becomes ultimately worthless, and reap the rewards of others. Some quorum would probably have to vote in new members.</li>
<li><strong>Failure</strong> -- what happens with failures? The entire point of the pool is to make something even when you fail.</li>
<li><strong>Dilution</strong> -- I imagine that founders probably just give x% of the equity when joining the fund and it just gets diluted out with future investment and such.  Can't do anything special here because we don't want the pool to penalize the companies chances of success (investors who don't like ugly cap tables or weird preferred shares)</li>
<li><strong>Variable Contribution/Buy-In</strong> -- maybe some founders only want to give up 1% and another founder wants to donate 10%. Should unequal contributions be allowed? Or just tell everybody they're in for 3% in return for an equal share of the resulting portfolio? If variable contributions are allowed, the pool quorum has to determine what amount of the prospective portfolio company they want in return</li>
<li><strong>Buying Out / Quitting</strong> -- Buying out your poriton of the pool? Is this legit? The pool doesn't want the next Heroku's founders to buy out their shares right before they know they're going to get bought.  At the same time, we don't want high performing companies to get penalized with the addition of a lot of garbage companies.</li>
<li><strong>Management Fee</strong> -- Legal isn't cheap. Give an attorney 30 basis points to keep him happy? And does the fund need a manager? Obviously as a participant, I want it to be as cheap as possible for myself, but I'd also love to not be the one in charge of managing this.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Why I want to do this</h2>

<p>I think this would be a fun idea, but I don't know if its feasible or what the details would have to look like. If you are a critic, please tell me why it sucks (and preferably, how it can be workable). If you are interested, please tell me so we can start scheming. <a href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Email me.</a></p>

<p>One cool thing about this is that it also gives participants a pool of other (hopefully high quality) founders that they are personally invested in seeing succeed. Participants might also see interesting dealflow from other early stage startups.</p>

<p>There doesn't have to be just one of these.  Any group of founder friends who is interested in equity swapping can do so, with their own private agreements.</p>

<p>This is the result of a conversation a few nights ago at 25 degrees with CG and CQ. I had previously also spoken with JF at the Brandery about this.  All have expressed some interest in exploring this, so might already have a few people in on this.</p>

<p><a style="color:#D20606; font-size:1.5em; text-decoration:underline;" href="mailto:ericzliu@gmail.com">Join in on the fun</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[YourSiteCouldLookLike.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/yoursitecouldlooklike-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old gym has a website that renders terribly on mobile, yet everybody at the gym goes to it every day to see the workout (that may sound weird, just trust me that it's a typical crossfit gym thing).</p>

<p>Everybody goes to the site every day to see ONE thing: the workout of the day.  Then you get there and have to pinch and zoom to read it.</p>

<p>I want a mobile version. So I threw together my own stylesheet for it. It'd be great if I could show my friends.</p>

<h2><strong>Somebody Please Build This</strong></h2>


<p><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com</strong></p>

<p>"Your Site Could Look Like" is a website. Sort of like <strong>bitly, but it doesn't just redirect, it loads the target page AND adds additional stylesheet rules</strong> to it. Basically, it lets you apply any css to any website and show it off to your friends (or the customer who you are trying to woo).</p>

<h2><strong>How it works</strong></h2>


<p>On the main page there are 2 input fields and a submit button.</p>

<blockquote>
<div>1) Target Site URL:</div>
<div>2) CSS file location:</div>
<div>3) [Submit button]</div>
</blockquote>


<p>User puts in a website and an alt stylesheet for it. On clicking submit, they get back a unique url:</p>

<blockquote>
<div><strong>http://yoursitecouldlooklike.com/xT6j2</strong></div></blockquote>


<p>Set up an nginx/apache reverse proxy. Whenever someone accesses that URL, the service curls the target site (1), inserts the contents of the CSS file immediately before the closing html tag (2), then serves the page to the customer.</p>

<p>If you want to be fancy, you can count page views, do analytics on the ip addresses that access it, etc. You can also let people insert their own js file. Will someone build this please?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
