<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: events | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-01-30T16:34:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes from Noah Kagan talk at Chicago Growth Hackers Meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/notes-from-noah-kagan-talk-at-chicago-growth-hackers-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T22:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/notes-from-noah-kagan-talk-at-chicago-growth-hackers-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended a small event where Noah Kagan spoke to us about his experience and answered audience questions very candidly.</p>

<h2>Screw A/B testing, just build the product YOU would use</h2>

<p>I suspect it's a question of how much you let testing dictate strategy and user experience over personal preference. Nerds (including me) often think"data solves all". However, sometimes it comes at a user experience penalty and you can make the conscious decision to ignore it.For example, forcing users to input an email address to see the deal -- tests will show more signups, but users hate it. Same for how news sites paginate articles to optimize ad revenue. Balance your testing with a dose of "what user experience do YOU want?". Obviously split testing and analytics are still valuable. It's impossible to distill out the nuances of a founder's startup philosophy in a 10 minute segment.</p>

<h2>If you're not doing what you love, you're doing it wrong</h2>

<p>Noah genuinely believes in what he does. He got sick of building crappy facebook games, then payments for crappy facebook games. Do what you love (groundbreaking advice, I know).</p>

<p>related: <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2235-work-on-your-best-idea">37 Signals</a></p>

<h2>By the time you read about a distribution channel on a blog somewhere, the market is probably saturated</h2>

<p>Anything you read on a "growth hacking" blog is probably not the best way to get users (basically, fb ads have jumped the shark). If you want to get real growth, real fast, think outside the box.</p>

<h2>"Its easier to go deal drugs at other people's parties than make everyone come to your party."</h2>

<p>Partner with people who already have your customers. Many startups build a product and want it to be the destination site. Instead of trying to drive people to your site and convert users, go to the sites where your users are already hanging out and partner/advertise/guest blog, whatever.  My favorite quote of the night.</p>

<h2>Be aggressive</h2>

<p>Go to your competitors forums, facebook fan page, or whatever and start messaging their customers directly. I'm a fan of this sort of thing for early stage startups. HN pooped on <a href="http://www.virool.com/blog/how-to-land-fortune-100-brand-for-a-startup/">Virool's "crash your competitor panel" story</a> but I was a fan of that too.</p>

<h2>ONE METRIC</h2>

<p>Another one I liked. You need to have one metric that is paramount to all others. Knowing what SINGLE metric is your stated "most important metric" makes all decisions easy.  In the early days of Appsumo, this was "number of email addresses". If deciding between multiple courses of action, the winner was the answer to the question: "Which one is expected to move the needle on the stated metric more?" This one i liked.  Startup nerds overcomplicate stuff. This helps get you into "just fucking do it" mode.  Does it guarantee that you're chasing the RIGHT metric? no. Does it simplify decision making to get you information faster so you can change that metric later? probably. Everything you do should be in pursuit of moving the needle on this.</p>

<h2>When You Should Fire</h2>

<p>if an employee costs X to keep and delivers value less than X, they need to be canned. it's that easy. i enjoyed this comment, but i imagine that a lot of people think its too reductionist and dehumanizing. it resonates with me though, so i guess i'm just a robot.</p>

<h2>Other interesting bits</h2>

<ul>
<li>Appsumo sends 20million emails a month, and it costs $3500, using sendgrid</li>
<li>Appsumo did 3.5mm in revenue last year and are on pace for 7mm this year.</li>
<li>Noah says he would open a smoothie and taco stand if he wasn't doing appsumo and didn't have to work. i find this amusing.</li>
<li>I enjoyed his anecdote for how they came up with the name "appsumo".</li>
<li>Noah seems to be obsessed with tacos. he meditates 15 minutes a day. he has a scooter. he loves whole foods.</li>
<li>he made the comment that he's good at thinking 6 months ahead of the curve, but guys like Andrew Chen are great at thinking 18 months ahead.</li>
</ul>


<p>I mostly just wanted to see what Noah Kagan was like in person. I had heard mixed reports about his personality (funny, nice, abrasive, sexist, awkward) and wanted to experience the insanity first hand.</p>

<p>I'll admit there was the "I love reality TV" part of me that was hoping he'd say something ridiculous and sensationalist, but I can't say that he was anything other than very nice, charismatic, outgoing, well spoken, and not socially awkward at all.</p>

<p>There are no outsiders when Noah's around.  Noah is fantastic at making everyone feel like they're a part of the dialogue.  This is an amazing skill. If he's talking to a group of people and someone is on the outskirts, noah will politely interrupt the conversation, ask the circle to expand, and bring the outside person into the conversation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
