<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: random | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-21T13:25:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What would you do if the world MIGHT end soon?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/what-would-you-do-if-the-world-might-end-soon/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T10:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/what-would-you-do-if-the-world-might-end-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was chatting to a friend about doomsday predictions for 12/21/2012 and wondered what I'd do if I thought that there was some credibility to the Mayan doomsday prophecy.</p>

<p><img src="/images/mayan_doomsday.png" alt="Mayan Doomsday" /></p>

<p>What if we could validate with certainty that there is a 75% chance that the world as we know it will end in 2 weeks.  As a thought experiment, imagine we have a credible threat against planet earth by an alien race.</p>

<p>These aliens have stated that they are going to roll a 4 sided die, and if the outcome is 4, they'll be our guardian protectors forever, but if the outcome is 1, 2, or 3 they will annihilate our planet.  This is unstoppable by us.  We believe the threat to be real because they have demonstrated their power by speaking to us and broadcasting the message to the entire planet from light years away (so they're too far away for us to even reach them, given our existing technology) and demonstrated their far superior technology.</p>

<p>Anyways, the point is: there is a 75% chance the world will end. There is a 25% chance it won't. What do you do with your next 2 weeks?</p>

<p>If you rape and pillage and spend all your money, then there's a 25% chance you'll be in trouble when they don't destroy our planet and life goes back to normal.</p>

<p>If you just go on living life, you'd be missing out on the opportunity to proclaim your love to your crush or blow your 401k on the lifestyle you could never have.</p>

<p>What would you do? How does that change if the odds of doomsday are increased to 90% or decreased to 10%?</p>

<p><img src="/images/ohpress.jpg" alt="Overhead Press" /></p>

<p>I was looking up crossfit related pictures yesterday. I love this picture and it's my blog so I get to do whatever I want. Booyah.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
