<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hustle | ezl]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/categories/hustle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-24T19:07:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ezliu.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ezl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ericzliu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create Value]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ezliu.com//blog/create-value/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-30T14:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ezliu.com//blog/create-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One lie that I'm consantly told is <em>"Early stage startups only need developers"</em>.</p>

<p>It typically comes in the context of <em>"I don't know how to program, but I want
to work for a startup. Unfortunately, early stage startups only need coders."</em></p>

<p>This is (a) <strong>false</strong>, and (b) <strong>an excuse</strong>.</p>

<h3>What Do Startups Need?</h3>

<p>Startups are a quest to make valuable things from ideas and sweat.  <strong>Early stage
startups need people who create value.</strong></p>

<p>While writing code is an easy way to feel like you're creating value, it's far from
the only way to create value.  If you can't code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Get customers / letters of intent</li>
<li>Make cold calls</li>
<li>Get lunch and coffee and dry cleaning for the developers so they can get the MVP out the door faster</li>
<li>Optimize adwords campaigns</li>
<li>Build buzz via social media</li>
<li>Get bloggers to write about you / do PR</li>
<li>Run focus groups</li>
<li>Find free office space for a team by calling other startups in the area and asking if any of them will host you.</li>
</ul>


<h3>How To Get A Job At Any Startup</h3>

<p><strong>You can get a job at ANY early stage startup by emailing the founder and telling him you'll create value for his/her team.</strong>  Here's a template:</p>

<blockquote>
Hi, my name is [name].<br>

I want to work for your startup, for free. I'm not a developer. I am smart,
hardworking, motivated, and a quick learner.<br><br>

I know you may not have a budget for a non-technical team member now, so I'd
like to intern at your company for no pay for 3 weeks. During that time, I
will do anything and everything to create value for your team.<br><br>

This costs you nothing. If at any time, you can't justify keeping me around,
we will both agree to amicably part ways and I will be grateful for the
experience. No expectations.<br><br>

Could I show up on Tuesday of next week to get started? We can consider it an interview. If it seems like a fit, I'll just get
started with seeing how I can add value to the team. If I don't hear an explicit "no" from you,
I'll see you on Tuesday!
</blockquote>


<p>Then you have 3 weeks to make yourself absolutely indispensible to that company.</p>

<h3>Why This Will Work?</h3>

<p>Here's a secret about startup founders: They like money. So if you can join
their team for free and make them richer, they'll be excited about paying you
to stick around. (Another hint: if they <em>don't</em> want free value creation, they
probably suck or it's not a fit)</p>

<p>If you CAN'T make yourself unquestionably indispensible in some way, then
you need to ask yourself whether you're really adding enough value for the
startup to consider hiring you.</p>

<p>The next time someone tells you that code is the most important thing, consider this:</p>

<p>It is <em>sometimes</em> possible to outsource code. It is <em>never</em> possible to
outsource strategy or business development.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
